<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?metadataRepository version='1.1.0'?>
<repository name='update site: http://rxtx.qbang.org/eclipse/' type='org.eclipse.equinox.internal.p2.metadata.repository.LocalMetadataRepository' version='1'>
  <properties size='2'>
    <property name='p2.timestamp' value='1312972690514'/>
    <property name='site.checksum' value='2763805992'/>
  </properties>
  <references size='4'>
    <repository uri='http://www.rxtx.org/eclipse' url='http://www.rxtx.org/eclipse' type='1' options='0'/>
    <repository uri='http://www.rxtx.org/eclipse' url='http://www.rxtx.org/eclipse' type='0' options='0'/>
    <repository uri='http://rxtx.qbang.org/eclipse' url='http://rxtx.qbang.org/eclipse' type='1' options='0'/>
    <repository uri='http://rxtx.qbang.org/eclipse' url='http://rxtx.qbang.org/eclipse' type='0' options='0'/>
  </references>
  <units size='24'>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20071015)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20071015&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20070718)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='1'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20070718&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20071015)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20071015&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20070717)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20070717&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.4_v20071016)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='1'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.4_v20071016&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.group' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.group' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='10'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='%featureName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='%description'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description.url' value='http://www.rxtx.org'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.provider' value='%providerName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.type.group' value='true'/>
        <property name='df_LT.featureName' value='RXTX End-User Runtime'/>
        <property name='df_LT.providerName' value='RXTX.org'/>
        <property name='df_LT.description' value='RXTX is a library to access serial ports from Java. '/>
        <property name='df_LT.copyright' value='Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.'/>
        <property name='df_LT.license' value='RXTX License v 2.1 - LGPL v 2.1 + Linking Over Controlled Interface.&#xA;RXTX is a native interface to serial ports in java.&#xA;&#xA;Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.&#xA;&#xA;A copy of the LGPL v 2.1 may be found at&#xA;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl.txt on March 4th 2007.  A copy is&#xA;included below for your convenience.&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;An executable that contains no derivative of any portion of RXTX, but&#xA;is designed to work with RXTX by being dynamically linked with it,&#xA;is considered a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; subject to the terms and&#xA;conditions of the GNU Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;The following has been added to the RXTX License to remove&#xA;any confusion about linking to RXTX.   We want to allow in part what&#xA;section 5, paragraph 2 of the LGPL does not permit in the special&#xA;case of linking over a controlled interface.  The intent is to add a&#xA;Java Specification Request or standards body defined interface in the&#xA;future as another exception but one is not currently available.&#xA;&#xA;http://www.fsf.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#LinkingOverControlledInterface&#xA;&#xA;As a special exception, the copyright holders of RXTX give you&#xA;permission to link RXTX with independent modules that communicate with&#xA;RXTX solely through the Sun Microsytems CommAPI interface version 2,&#xA;regardless of the license terms of these independent modules, and to copy&#xA;and distribute the resulting combined work under terms of your choice,&#xA;provided that every copy of the combined work is accompanied by a complete&#xA;copy of the source code of RXTX (the version of RXTX used to produce the&#xA;combined work), being distributed under the terms of the GNU Lesser General&#xA;Public License plus this exception.  An independent module is a&#xA;module which is not derived from or based on RXTX.&#xA;&#xA;Note that people who make modified versions of RXTX are not obligated&#xA;to grant this special exception for their modified versions; it is&#xA;their choice whether to do so.  The GNU Lesser General Public License&#xA;gives permission to release a modified version without this exception; this&#xA;exception also makes it possible to release a modified version which&#xA;carries forward this exception.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA&#xA;All trademarks belong to their respective owners.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;Version 2.1, February 1999&#xA;&#xA;Copyright (C) 1991, 1999 Free Software Foundation, Inc.&#xA;51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies&#xA;of this license document, but changing it is not allowed.&#xA;&#xA;[This is the first released version of the Lesser GPL.  It also counts&#xA;as the successor of the GNU Library Public License, version 2, hence&#xA;the version number 2.1.]&#xA;&#xA;Preamble&#xA;&#xA;The licenses for most software are designed to take away your&#xA;freedom to share and change it.  By contrast, the GNU General Public&#xA;Licenses are intended to guarantee your freedom to share and change&#xA;free software--to make sure the software is free for all its users.&#xA;&#xA;This license, the Lesser General Public License, applies to some&#xA;specially designated software packages--typically libraries--of the&#xA;Free Software Foundation and other authors who decide to use it.  You&#xA;can use it too, but we suggest you first think carefully about whether&#xA;this license or the ordinary General Public License is the better&#xA;strategy to use in any particular case, based on the explanations below.&#xA;&#xA;When we speak of free software, we are referring to freedom of use,&#xA;not price.  Our General Public Licenses are designed to make sure that&#xA;you have the freedom to distribute copies of free software (and charge&#xA;for this service if you wish); that you receive source code or can get&#xA;it if you want it; that you can change the software and use pieces of&#xA;it in new free programs; and that you are informed that you can do&#xA;these things.&#xA;&#xA;To protect your rights, we need to make restrictions that forbid&#xA;distributors to deny you these rights or to ask you to surrender these&#xA;rights.  These restrictions translate to certain responsibilities for&#xA;you if you distribute copies of the library or if you modify it.&#xA;&#xA;For example, if you distribute copies of the library, whether gratis&#xA;or for a fee, you must give the recipients all the rights that we gave&#xA;you.  You must make sure that they, too, receive or can get the source&#xA;code.  If you link other code with the library, you must provide&#xA;complete object files to the recipients, so that they can relink them&#xA;with the library after making changes to the library and recompiling&#xA;it.  And you must show them these terms so they know their rights.&#xA;&#xA;We protect your rights with a two-step method: (1) we copyright the&#xA;library, and (2) we offer you this license, which gives you legal&#xA;permission to copy, distribute and/or modify the library.&#xA;&#xA;To protect each distributor, we want to make it very clear that&#xA;there is no warranty for the free library.  Also, if the library is&#xA;modified by someone else and passed on, the recipients should know&#xA;that what they have is not the original version, so that the original&#xA;author&apos;s reputation will not be affected by problems that might be&#xA;introduced by others.&#xA;&#xA;Finally, software patents pose a constant threat to the existence of&#xA;any free program.  We wish to make sure that a company cannot&#xA;effectively restrict the users of a free program by obtaining a&#xA;restrictive license from a patent holder.  Therefore, we insist that&#xA;any patent license obtained for a version of the library must be&#xA;consistent with the full freedom of use specified in this license.&#xA;&#xA;Most GNU software, including some libraries, is covered by the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License.  This license, the GNU Lesser&#xA;General Public License, applies to certain designated libraries, and&#xA;is quite different from the ordinary General Public License.  We use&#xA;this license for certain libraries in order to permit linking those&#xA;libraries into non-free programs.&#xA;&#xA;When a program is linked with a library, whether statically or using&#xA;a shared library, the combination of the two is legally speaking a&#xA;combined work, a derivative of the original library.  The ordinary&#xA;General Public License therefore permits such linking only if the&#xA;entire combination fits its criteria of freedom.  The Lesser General&#xA;Public License permits more lax criteria for linking other code with&#xA;the library.&#xA;&#xA;We call this license the &quot;Lesser&quot; General Public License because it&#xA;does Less to protect the user&apos;s freedom than the ordinary General&#xA;Public License.  It also provides other free software developers Less&#xA;of an advantage over competing non-free programs.  These disadvantages&#xA;are the reason we use the ordinary General Public License for many&#xA;libraries.  However, the Lesser license provides advantages in certain&#xA;special circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;For example, on rare occasions, there may be a special need to&#xA;encourage the widest possible use of a certain library, so that it becomes&#xA;a de-facto standard.  To achieve this, non-free programs must be&#xA;allowed to use the library.  A more frequent case is that a free&#xA;library does the same job as widely used non-free libraries.  In this&#xA;case, there is little to gain by limiting the free library to free&#xA;software only, so we use the Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;In other cases, permission to use a particular library in non-free&#xA;programs enables a greater number of people to use a large body of&#xA;free software.  For example, permission to use the GNU C Library in&#xA;non-free programs enables many more people to use the whole GNU&#xA;operating system, as well as its variant, the GNU/Linux operating&#xA;system.&#xA;&#xA;Although the Lesser General Public License is Less protective of the&#xA;users&apos; freedom, it does ensure that the user of a program that is&#xA;linked with the Library has the freedom and the wherewithal to run&#xA;that program using a modified version of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;The precise terms and conditions for copying, distribution and&#xA;modification follow.  Pay close attention to the difference between a&#xA;&quot;work based on the library&quot; and a &quot;work that uses the library&quot;.  The&#xA;former contains code derived from the library, whereas the latter must&#xA;be combined with the library in order to run.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR COPYING, DISTRIBUTION AND MODIFICATION&#xA;&#xA;0. This License Agreement applies to any software library or other&#xA;program which contains a notice placed by the copyright holder or&#xA;other authorized party saying it may be distributed under the terms of&#xA;this Lesser General Public License (also called &quot;this License&quot;).&#xA;Each licensee is addressed as &quot;you&quot;.&#xA;&#xA;A &quot;library&quot; means a collection of software functions and/or data&#xA;prepared so as to be conveniently linked with application programs&#xA;(which use some of those functions and data) to form executables.&#xA;&#xA;The &quot;Library&quot;, below, refers to any such software library or work&#xA;which has been distributed under these terms.  A &quot;work based on the&#xA;Library&quot; means either the Library or any derivative work under&#xA;copyright law: that is to say, a work containing the Library or a&#xA;portion of it, either verbatim or with modifications and/or translated&#xA;straightforwardly into another language.  (Hereinafter, translation is&#xA;included without limitation in the term &quot;modification&quot;.)&#xA;&#xA;&quot;Source code&quot; for a work means the preferred form of the work for&#xA;making modifications to it.  For a library, complete source code means&#xA;all the source code for all modules it contains, plus any associated&#xA;interface definition files, plus the scripts used to control compilation&#xA;and installation of the library.&#xA;&#xA;Activities other than copying, distribution and modification are not&#xA;covered by this License; they are outside its scope.  The act of&#xA;running a program using the Library is not restricted, and output from&#xA;such a program is covered only if its contents constitute a work based&#xA;on the Library (independent of the use of the Library in a tool for&#xA;writing it).  Whether that is true depends on what the Library does&#xA;and what the program that uses the Library does.&#xA;&#xA;1. You may copy and distribute verbatim copies of the Library&apos;s&#xA;complete source code as you receive it, in any medium, provided that&#xA;you conspicuously and appropriately publish on each copy an&#xA;appropriate copyright notice and disclaimer of warranty; keep intact&#xA;all the notices that refer to this License and to the absence of any&#xA;warranty; and distribute a copy of this License along with the&#xA;Library.&#xA;&#xA;You may charge a fee for the physical act of transferring a copy,&#xA;and you may at your option offer warranty protection in exchange for a&#xA;fee.&#xA;&#xA;2. You may modify your copy or copies of the Library or any portion&#xA;of it, thus forming a work based on the Library, and copy and&#xA;distribute such modifications or work under the terms of Section 1&#xA;above, provided that you also meet all of these conditions:&#xA;&#xA;a) The modified work must itself be a software library.&#xA;&#xA;b) You must cause the files modified to carry prominent notices&#xA;stating that you changed the files and the date of any change.&#xA;&#xA;c) You must cause the whole of the work to be licensed at no&#xA;charge to all third parties under the terms of this License.&#xA;&#xA;d) If a facility in the modified Library refers to a function or a&#xA;table of data to be supplied by an application program that uses&#xA;the facility, other than as an argument passed when the facility&#xA;is invoked, then you must make a good faith effort to ensure that,&#xA;in the event an application does not supply such function or&#xA;table, the facility still operates, and performs whatever part of&#xA;its purpose remains meaningful.&#xA;&#xA;(For example, a function in a library to compute square roots has&#xA;a purpose that is entirely well-defined independent of the&#xA;application.  Therefore, Subsection 2d requires that any&#xA;application-supplied function or table used by this function must&#xA;be optional: if the application does not supply it, the square&#xA;root function must still compute square roots.)&#xA;&#xA;These requirements apply to the modified work as a whole.  If&#xA;identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Library,&#xA;and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in&#xA;themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those&#xA;sections when you distribute them as separate works.  But when you&#xA;distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based&#xA;on the Library, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of&#xA;this License, whose permissions for other licensees extend to the&#xA;entire whole, and thus to each and every part regardless of who wrote&#xA;it.&#xA;&#xA;Thus, it is not the intent of this section to claim rights or contest&#xA;your rights to work written entirely by you; rather, the intent is to&#xA;exercise the right to control the distribution of derivative or&#xA;collective works based on the Library.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, mere aggregation of another work not based on the Library&#xA;with the Library (or with a work based on the Library) on a volume of&#xA;a storage or distribution medium does not bring the other work under&#xA;the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;3. You may opt to apply the terms of the ordinary GNU General Public&#xA;License instead of this License to a given copy of the Library.  To do&#xA;this, you must alter all the notices that refer to this License, so&#xA;that they refer to the ordinary GNU General Public License, version 2,&#xA;instead of to this License.  (If a newer version than version 2 of the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License has appeared, then you can specify&#xA;that version instead if you wish.)  Do not make any other change in&#xA;these notices.&#xA;&#xA;Once this change is made in a given copy, it is irreversible for&#xA;that copy, so the ordinary GNU General Public License applies to all&#xA;subsequent copies and derivative works made from that copy.&#xA;&#xA;This option is useful when you wish to copy part of the code of&#xA;the Library into a program that is not a library.&#xA;&#xA;4. You may copy and distribute the Library (or a portion or&#xA;derivative of it, under Section 2) in object code or executable form&#xA;under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above provided that you accompany&#xA;it with the complete corresponding machine-readable source code, which&#xA;must be distributed under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above on a&#xA;medium customarily used for software interchange.&#xA;&#xA;If distribution of object code is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, then offering equivalent access to copy the&#xA;source code from the same place satisfies the requirement to&#xA;distribute the source code, even though third parties are not&#xA;compelled to copy the source along with the object code.&#xA;&#xA;5. A program that contains no derivative of any portion of the&#xA;Library, but is designed to work with the Library by being compiled or&#xA;linked with it, is called a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot;.  Such a&#xA;work, in isolation, is not a derivative work of the Library, and&#xA;therefore falls outside the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;However, linking a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library&#xA;creates an executable that is a derivative of the Library (because it&#xA;contains portions of the Library), rather than a &quot;work that uses the&#xA;library&quot;.  The executable is therefore covered by this License.&#xA;Section 6 states terms for distribution of such executables.&#xA;&#xA;When a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; uses material from a header file&#xA;that is part of the Library, the object code for the work may be a&#xA;derivative work of the Library even though the source code is not.&#xA;Whether this is true is especially significant if the work can be&#xA;linked without the Library, or if the work is itself a library.  The&#xA;threshold for this to be true is not precisely defined by law.&#xA;&#xA;If such an object file uses only numerical parameters, data&#xA;structure layouts and accessors, and small macros and small inline&#xA;functions (ten lines or less in length), then the use of the object&#xA;file is unrestricted, regardless of whether it is legally a derivative&#xA;work.  (Executables containing this object code plus portions of the&#xA;Library will still fall under Section 6.)&#xA;&#xA;Otherwise, if the work is a derivative of the Library, you may&#xA;distribute the object code for the work under the terms of Section 6.&#xA;Any executables containing that work also fall under Section 6,&#xA;whether or not they are linked directly with the Library itself.&#xA;&#xA;6. As an exception to the Sections above, you may also combine or&#xA;link a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library to produce a&#xA;work containing portions of the Library, and distribute that work&#xA;under terms of your choice, provided that the terms permit&#xA;modification of the work for the customer&apos;s own use and reverse&#xA;engineering for debugging such modifications.&#xA;&#xA;You must give prominent notice with each copy of the work that the&#xA;Library is used in it and that the Library and its use are covered by&#xA;this License.  You must supply a copy of this License.  If the work&#xA;during execution displays copyright notices, you must include the&#xA;copyright notice for the Library among them, as well as a reference&#xA;directing the user to the copy of this License.  Also, you must do one&#xA;of these things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the work with the complete corresponding&#xA;machine-readable source code for the Library including whatever&#xA;changes were used in the work (which must be distributed under&#xA;Sections 1 and 2 above); and, if the work is an executable linked&#xA;with the Library, with the complete machine-readable &quot;work that&#xA;uses the Library&quot;, as object code and/or source code, so that the&#xA;user can modify the Library and then relink to produce a modified&#xA;executable containing the modified Library.  (It is understood&#xA;that the user who changes the contents of definitions files in the&#xA;Library will not necessarily be able to recompile the application&#xA;to use the modified definitions.)&#xA;&#xA;b) Use a suitable shared library mechanism for linking with the&#xA;Library.  A suitable mechanism is one that (1) uses at run time a&#xA;copy of the library already present on the user&apos;s computer system,&#xA;rather than copying library functions into the executable, and (2)&#xA;will operate properly with a modified version of the library, if&#xA;the user installs one, as long as the modified version is&#xA;interface-compatible with the version that the work was made with.&#xA;&#xA;c) Accompany the work with a written offer, valid for at&#xA;least three years, to give the same user the materials&#xA;specified in Subsection 6a, above, for a charge no more&#xA;than the cost of performing this distribution.&#xA;&#xA;d) If distribution of the work is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, offer equivalent access to copy the above&#xA;specified materials from the same place.&#xA;&#xA;e) Verify that the user has already received a copy of these&#xA;materials or that you have already sent this user a copy.&#xA;&#xA;For an executable, the required form of the &quot;work that uses the&#xA;Library&quot; must include any data and utility programs needed for&#xA;reproducing the executable from it.  However, as a special exception,&#xA;the materials to be distributed need not include anything that is&#xA;normally distributed (in either source or binary form) with the major&#xA;components (compiler, kernel, and so on) of the operating system on&#xA;which the executable runs, unless that component itself accompanies&#xA;the executable.&#xA;&#xA;It may happen that this requirement contradicts the license&#xA;restrictions of other proprietary libraries that do not normally&#xA;accompany the operating system.  Such a contradiction means you cannot&#xA;use both them and the Library together in an executable that you&#xA;distribute.&#xA;&#xA;7. You may place library facilities that are a work based on the&#xA;Library side-by-side in a single library together with other library&#xA;facilities not covered by this License, and distribute such a combined&#xA;library, provided that the separate distribution of the work based on&#xA;the Library and of the other library facilities is otherwise&#xA;permitted, and provided that you do these two things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the combined library with a copy of the same work&#xA;based on the Library, uncombined with any other library&#xA;facilities.  This must be distributed under the terms of the&#xA;Sections above.&#xA;&#xA;b) Give prominent notice with the combined library of the fact&#xA;that part of it is a work based on the Library, and explaining&#xA;where to find the accompanying uncombined form of the same work.&#xA;&#xA;8. You may not copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or distribute&#xA;the Library except as expressly provided under this License.  Any&#xA;attempt otherwise to copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or&#xA;distribute the Library is void, and will automatically terminate your&#xA;rights under this License.  However, parties who have received copies,&#xA;or rights, from you under this License will not have their licenses&#xA;terminated so long as such parties remain in full compliance.&#xA;&#xA;9. You are not required to accept this License, since you have not&#xA;signed it.  However, nothing else grants you permission to modify or&#xA;distribute the Library or its derivative works.  These actions are&#xA;prohibited by law if you do not accept this License.  Therefore, by&#xA;modifying or distributing the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), you indicate your acceptance of this License to do so, and&#xA;all its terms and conditions for copying, distributing or modifying&#xA;the Library or works based on it.&#xA;&#xA;10. Each time you redistribute the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), the recipient automatically receives a license from the&#xA;original licensor to copy, distribute, link with or modify the Library&#xA;subject to these terms and conditions.  You may not impose any further&#xA;restrictions on the recipients&apos; exercise of the rights granted herein.&#xA;You are not responsible for enforcing compliance by third parties with&#xA;this License.&#xA;&#xA;11. If, as a consequence of a court judgment or allegation of patent&#xA;infringement or for any other reason (not limited to patent issues),&#xA;conditions are imposed on you (whether by court order, agreement or&#xA;otherwise) that contradict the conditions of this License, they do not&#xA;excuse you from the conditions of this License.  If you cannot&#xA;distribute so as to satisfy simultaneously your obligations under this&#xA;License and any other pertinent obligations, then as a consequence you&#xA;may not distribute the Library at all.  For example, if a patent&#xA;license would not permit royalty-free redistribution of the Library by&#xA;all those who receive copies directly or indirectly through you, then&#xA;the only way you could satisfy both it and this License would be to&#xA;refrain entirely from distribution of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;If any portion of this section is held invalid or unenforceable under any&#xA;particular circumstance, the balance of the section is intended to apply,&#xA;and the section as a whole is intended to apply in other circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;It is not the purpose of this section to induce you to infringe any&#xA;patents or other property right claims or to contest validity of any&#xA;such claims; this section has the sole purpose of protecting the&#xA;integrity of the free software distribution system which is&#xA;implemented by public license practices.  Many people have made&#xA;generous contributions to the wide range of software distributed&#xA;through that system in reliance on consistent application of that&#xA;system; it is up to the author/donor to decide if he or she is willing&#xA;to distribute software through any other system and a licensee cannot&#xA;impose that choice.&#xA;&#xA;This section is intended to make thoroughly clear what is believed to&#xA;be a consequence of the rest of this License.&#xA;&#xA;12. If the distribution and/or use of the Library is restricted in&#xA;certain countries either by patents or by copyrighted interfaces, the&#xA;original copyright holder who places the Library under this License may add&#xA;an explicit geographical distribution limitation excluding those countries,&#xA;so that distribution is permitted only in or among countries not thus&#xA;excluded.  In such case, this License incorporates the limitation as if&#xA;written in the body of this License.&#xA;&#xA;13. The Free Software Foundation may publish revised and/or new&#xA;versions of the Lesser General Public License from time to time.&#xA;Such new versions will be similar in spirit to the present version,&#xA;but may differ in detail to address new problems or concerns.&#xA;&#xA;Each version is given a distinguishing version number.  If the Library&#xA;specifies a version number of this License which applies to it and&#xA;&quot;any later version&quot;, you have the option of following the terms and&#xA;conditions either of that version or of any later version published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.  If the Library does not specify a&#xA;license version number, you may choose any version ever published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.&#xA;&#xA;14. If you wish to incorporate parts of the Library into other free&#xA;programs whose distribution conditions are incompatible with these,&#xA;write to the author to ask for permission.  For software which is&#xA;copyrighted by the Free Software Foundation, write to the Free&#xA;Software Foundation; we sometimes make exceptions for this.  Our&#xA;decision will be guided by the two goals of preserving the free status&#xA;of all derivatives of our free software and of promoting the sharing&#xA;and reuse of software generally.&#xA;&#xA;NO WARRANTY&#xA;&#xA;15. BECAUSE THE LIBRARY IS LICENSED FREE OF CHARGE, THERE IS NO&#xA;WARRANTY FOR THE LIBRARY, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW.&#xA;EXCEPT WHEN OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND/OR&#xA;OTHER PARTIES PROVIDE THE LIBRARY &quot;AS IS&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY&#xA;KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE&#xA;IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR&#xA;PURPOSE.  THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE&#xA;LIBRARY IS WITH YOU.  SHOULD THE LIBRARY PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME&#xA;THE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.&#xA;&#xA;16. IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN&#xA;WRITING WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MAY MODIFY&#xA;AND/OR REDISTRIBUTE THE LIBRARY AS PERMITTED ABOVE, BE LIABLE TO YOU&#xA;FOR DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR&#xA;CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE&#xA;LIBRARY (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF DATA OR DATA BEING&#xA;RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY YOU OR THIRD PARTIES OR A&#xA;FAILURE OF THE LIBRARY TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER SOFTWARE), EVEN IF&#xA;SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH&#xA;DAMAGES.&#xA;&#xA;END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS&#xA;&#xA;How to Apply These Terms to Your New Libraries&#xA;&#xA;If you develop a new library, and you want it to be of the greatest&#xA;possible use to the public, we recommend making it free software that&#xA;everyone can redistribute and change.  You can do so by permitting&#xA;redistribution under these terms (or, alternatively, under the terms of the&#xA;ordinary General Public License).&#xA;&#xA;To apply these terms, attach the following notices to the library.  It is&#xA;safest to attach them to the start of each source file to most effectively&#xA;convey the exclusion of warranty; and each file should have at least the&#xA;&quot;copyright&quot; line and a pointer to where the full notice is found.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;one line to give the library&apos;s name and a brief idea of what it does.&gt;&#xA;Copyright (C) &lt;year&gt;  &lt;name of author&gt;&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;&#xA;Also add information on how to contact you by electronic and paper mail.&#xA;&#xA;You should also get your employer (if you work as a programmer) or your&#xA;school, if any, to sign a &quot;copyright disclaimer&quot; for the library, if&#xA;necessary.  Here is a sample; alter the names:&#xA;&#xA;Yoyodyne, Inc., hereby disclaims all copyright interest in the&#xA;library `Frob&apos; (a library for tweaking knobs) written by James Random Hacker.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;signature of Ty Coon&gt;, 1 April 1990&#xA;Ty Coon, President of Vice&#xA;&#xA;That&apos;s all there is to it!'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='2'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.group' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.localization' name='df_LT' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <requires size='7'>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx' range='[2.1.7.4_v20071016,2.1.7.4_v20071016]'/>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' range='[2.1.7.3_v20071015,2.1.7.3_v20071015]'>
          <filter>
            (&amp;(osgi.arch=x86)(osgi.os=linux))
          </filter>
        </required>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' range='[2.1.7.3_v20071015,2.1.7.3_v20071015]'>
          <filter>
            (&amp;(osgi.arch=x86_64)(osgi.os=linux))
          </filter>
        </required>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' range='[2.1.7.3_v20071015,2.1.7.3_v20071015]'>
          <filter>
            (osgi.os=macosx)
          </filter>
        </required>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' range='[2.1.7.3_v20071015,2.1.7.3_v20071015]'>
          <filter>
            (&amp;(osgi.arch=sparc)(osgi.os=solaris))
          </filter>
        </required>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' range='[2.1.7.3_v20071015,2.1.7.3_v20071015]'>
          <filter>
            (&amp;(osgi.arch=x86)(osgi.os=win32))
          </filter>
        </required>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.jar' range='[2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf,2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf]'>
          <filter>
            (org.eclipse.update.install.features=true)
          </filter>
        </required>
      </requires>
      <touchpoint id='null' version='0.0.0'/>
      <licenses size='1'>
        <license uri='%25licenseURL' url='%25licenseURL'>
          %license
        </license>
      </licenses>
      <copyright uri='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html' url='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html'>
        %copyright
      </copyright>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20070717)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.macosx&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20070717&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20071015)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20071015&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='http://rxtx.qbang.org/eclipse/site.xml.RXTX 2.1-7r3' version='1.0.0.7837QcJZh_h7InhE77Y7YAc3SWUlblrVZAnjBrbL_jRjd'>
      <properties size='3'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='RXTX 2.1-7r3'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='RXTX 2.1-7r2 plus disable-version-output (RXTXCommDriver v1.16.2.57, RXTX bug 71), disable-lockfiles, sparc-sun-solaris2.7 support (RXTX bug 73)'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.type.category' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='1'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='http://rxtx.qbang.org/eclipse/site.xml.RXTX 2.1-7r3' version='1.0.0.7837QcJZh_h7InhE77Y7YAc3SWUlblrVZAnjBrbL_jRjd'/>
      </provides>
      <requires size='2'>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.group' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr,2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr]'/>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.group' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs,2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs]'/>
      </requires>
      <touchpoint id='null' version='0.0.0'/>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.source' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.source' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20070718)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.source' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.source' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.source' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.source&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20070718&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.jar' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs'>
      <properties size='10'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='%featureName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='%description'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description.url' value='http://www.rxtx.org'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.provider' value='%providerName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.update.feature.plugin' value='gnu.io.rxtx'/>
        <property name='df_LT.featureName' value='RXTX Extender SDK'/>
        <property name='df_LT.providerName' value='RXTX.org'/>
        <property name='df_LT.description' value='RXTX is a library to access serial ports from Java. The SDK Includes End-User Runtime and Source. '/>
        <property name='df_LT.copyright' value='Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.'/>
        <property name='df_LT.license' value='RXTX License v 2.1 - LGPL v 2.1 + Linking Over Controlled Interface.&#xA;RXTX is a native interface to serial ports in java.&#xA;&#xA;Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.&#xA;&#xA;A copy of the LGPL v 2.1 may be found at&#xA;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl.txt on March 4th 2007.  A copy is&#xA;included below for your convenience.&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;An executable that contains no derivative of any portion of RXTX, but&#xA;is designed to work with RXTX by being dynamically linked with it,&#xA;is considered a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; subject to the terms and&#xA;conditions of the GNU Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;The following has been added to the RXTX License to remove&#xA;any confusion about linking to RXTX.   We want to allow in part what&#xA;section 5, paragraph 2 of the LGPL does not permit in the special&#xA;case of linking over a controlled interface.  The intent is to add a&#xA;Java Specification Request or standards body defined interface in the&#xA;future as another exception but one is not currently available.&#xA;&#xA;http://www.fsf.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#LinkingOverControlledInterface&#xA;&#xA;As a special exception, the copyright holders of RXTX give you&#xA;permission to link RXTX with independent modules that communicate with&#xA;RXTX solely through the Sun Microsytems CommAPI interface version 2,&#xA;regardless of the license terms of these independent modules, and to copy&#xA;and distribute the resulting combined work under terms of your choice,&#xA;provided that every copy of the combined work is accompanied by a complete&#xA;copy of the source code of RXTX (the version of RXTX used to produce the&#xA;combined work), being distributed under the terms of the GNU Lesser General&#xA;Public License plus this exception.  An independent module is a&#xA;module which is not derived from or based on RXTX.&#xA;&#xA;Note that people who make modified versions of RXTX are not obligated&#xA;to grant this special exception for their modified versions; it is&#xA;their choice whether to do so.  The GNU Lesser General Public License&#xA;gives permission to release a modified version without this exception; this&#xA;exception also makes it possible to release a modified version which&#xA;carries forward this exception.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA&#xA;All trademarks belong to their respective owners.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;Version 2.1, February 1999&#xA;&#xA;Copyright (C) 1991, 1999 Free Software Foundation, Inc.&#xA;51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies&#xA;of this license document, but changing it is not allowed.&#xA;&#xA;[This is the first released version of the Lesser GPL.  It also counts&#xA;as the successor of the GNU Library Public License, version 2, hence&#xA;the version number 2.1.]&#xA;&#xA;Preamble&#xA;&#xA;The licenses for most software are designed to take away your&#xA;freedom to share and change it.  By contrast, the GNU General Public&#xA;Licenses are intended to guarantee your freedom to share and change&#xA;free software--to make sure the software is free for all its users.&#xA;&#xA;This license, the Lesser General Public License, applies to some&#xA;specially designated software packages--typically libraries--of the&#xA;Free Software Foundation and other authors who decide to use it.  You&#xA;can use it too, but we suggest you first think carefully about whether&#xA;this license or the ordinary General Public License is the better&#xA;strategy to use in any particular case, based on the explanations below.&#xA;&#xA;When we speak of free software, we are referring to freedom of use,&#xA;not price.  Our General Public Licenses are designed to make sure that&#xA;you have the freedom to distribute copies of free software (and charge&#xA;for this service if you wish); that you receive source code or can get&#xA;it if you want it; that you can change the software and use pieces of&#xA;it in new free programs; and that you are informed that you can do&#xA;these things.&#xA;&#xA;To protect your rights, we need to make restrictions that forbid&#xA;distributors to deny you these rights or to ask you to surrender these&#xA;rights.  These restrictions translate to certain responsibilities for&#xA;you if you distribute copies of the library or if you modify it.&#xA;&#xA;For example, if you distribute copies of the library, whether gratis&#xA;or for a fee, you must give the recipients all the rights that we gave&#xA;you.  You must make sure that they, too, receive or can get the source&#xA;code.  If you link other code with the library, you must provide&#xA;complete object files to the recipients, so that they can relink them&#xA;with the library after making changes to the library and recompiling&#xA;it.  And you must show them these terms so they know their rights.&#xA;&#xA;We protect your rights with a two-step method: (1) we copyright the&#xA;library, and (2) we offer you this license, which gives you legal&#xA;permission to copy, distribute and/or modify the library.&#xA;&#xA;To protect each distributor, we want to make it very clear that&#xA;there is no warranty for the free library.  Also, if the library is&#xA;modified by someone else and passed on, the recipients should know&#xA;that what they have is not the original version, so that the original&#xA;author&apos;s reputation will not be affected by problems that might be&#xA;introduced by others.&#xA;&#xA;Finally, software patents pose a constant threat to the existence of&#xA;any free program.  We wish to make sure that a company cannot&#xA;effectively restrict the users of a free program by obtaining a&#xA;restrictive license from a patent holder.  Therefore, we insist that&#xA;any patent license obtained for a version of the library must be&#xA;consistent with the full freedom of use specified in this license.&#xA;&#xA;Most GNU software, including some libraries, is covered by the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License.  This license, the GNU Lesser&#xA;General Public License, applies to certain designated libraries, and&#xA;is quite different from the ordinary General Public License.  We use&#xA;this license for certain libraries in order to permit linking those&#xA;libraries into non-free programs.&#xA;&#xA;When a program is linked with a library, whether statically or using&#xA;a shared library, the combination of the two is legally speaking a&#xA;combined work, a derivative of the original library.  The ordinary&#xA;General Public License therefore permits such linking only if the&#xA;entire combination fits its criteria of freedom.  The Lesser General&#xA;Public License permits more lax criteria for linking other code with&#xA;the library.&#xA;&#xA;We call this license the &quot;Lesser&quot; General Public License because it&#xA;does Less to protect the user&apos;s freedom than the ordinary General&#xA;Public License.  It also provides other free software developers Less&#xA;of an advantage over competing non-free programs.  These disadvantages&#xA;are the reason we use the ordinary General Public License for many&#xA;libraries.  However, the Lesser license provides advantages in certain&#xA;special circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;For example, on rare occasions, there may be a special need to&#xA;encourage the widest possible use of a certain library, so that it becomes&#xA;a de-facto standard.  To achieve this, non-free programs must be&#xA;allowed to use the library.  A more frequent case is that a free&#xA;library does the same job as widely used non-free libraries.  In this&#xA;case, there is little to gain by limiting the free library to free&#xA;software only, so we use the Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;In other cases, permission to use a particular library in non-free&#xA;programs enables a greater number of people to use a large body of&#xA;free software.  For example, permission to use the GNU C Library in&#xA;non-free programs enables many more people to use the whole GNU&#xA;operating system, as well as its variant, the GNU/Linux operating&#xA;system.&#xA;&#xA;Although the Lesser General Public License is Less protective of the&#xA;users&apos; freedom, it does ensure that the user of a program that is&#xA;linked with the Library has the freedom and the wherewithal to run&#xA;that program using a modified version of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;The precise terms and conditions for copying, distribution and&#xA;modification follow.  Pay close attention to the difference between a&#xA;&quot;work based on the library&quot; and a &quot;work that uses the library&quot;.  The&#xA;former contains code derived from the library, whereas the latter must&#xA;be combined with the library in order to run.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR COPYING, DISTRIBUTION AND MODIFICATION&#xA;&#xA;0. This License Agreement applies to any software library or other&#xA;program which contains a notice placed by the copyright holder or&#xA;other authorized party saying it may be distributed under the terms of&#xA;this Lesser General Public License (also called &quot;this License&quot;).&#xA;Each licensee is addressed as &quot;you&quot;.&#xA;&#xA;A &quot;library&quot; means a collection of software functions and/or data&#xA;prepared so as to be conveniently linked with application programs&#xA;(which use some of those functions and data) to form executables.&#xA;&#xA;The &quot;Library&quot;, below, refers to any such software library or work&#xA;which has been distributed under these terms.  A &quot;work based on the&#xA;Library&quot; means either the Library or any derivative work under&#xA;copyright law: that is to say, a work containing the Library or a&#xA;portion of it, either verbatim or with modifications and/or translated&#xA;straightforwardly into another language.  (Hereinafter, translation is&#xA;included without limitation in the term &quot;modification&quot;.)&#xA;&#xA;&quot;Source code&quot; for a work means the preferred form of the work for&#xA;making modifications to it.  For a library, complete source code means&#xA;all the source code for all modules it contains, plus any associated&#xA;interface definition files, plus the scripts used to control compilation&#xA;and installation of the library.&#xA;&#xA;Activities other than copying, distribution and modification are not&#xA;covered by this License; they are outside its scope.  The act of&#xA;running a program using the Library is not restricted, and output from&#xA;such a program is covered only if its contents constitute a work based&#xA;on the Library (independent of the use of the Library in a tool for&#xA;writing it).  Whether that is true depends on what the Library does&#xA;and what the program that uses the Library does.&#xA;&#xA;1. You may copy and distribute verbatim copies of the Library&apos;s&#xA;complete source code as you receive it, in any medium, provided that&#xA;you conspicuously and appropriately publish on each copy an&#xA;appropriate copyright notice and disclaimer of warranty; keep intact&#xA;all the notices that refer to this License and to the absence of any&#xA;warranty; and distribute a copy of this License along with the&#xA;Library.&#xA;&#xA;You may charge a fee for the physical act of transferring a copy,&#xA;and you may at your option offer warranty protection in exchange for a&#xA;fee.&#xA;&#xA;2. You may modify your copy or copies of the Library or any portion&#xA;of it, thus forming a work based on the Library, and copy and&#xA;distribute such modifications or work under the terms of Section 1&#xA;above, provided that you also meet all of these conditions:&#xA;&#xA;a) The modified work must itself be a software library.&#xA;&#xA;b) You must cause the files modified to carry prominent notices&#xA;stating that you changed the files and the date of any change.&#xA;&#xA;c) You must cause the whole of the work to be licensed at no&#xA;charge to all third parties under the terms of this License.&#xA;&#xA;d) If a facility in the modified Library refers to a function or a&#xA;table of data to be supplied by an application program that uses&#xA;the facility, other than as an argument passed when the facility&#xA;is invoked, then you must make a good faith effort to ensure that,&#xA;in the event an application does not supply such function or&#xA;table, the facility still operates, and performs whatever part of&#xA;its purpose remains meaningful.&#xA;&#xA;(For example, a function in a library to compute square roots has&#xA;a purpose that is entirely well-defined independent of the&#xA;application.  Therefore, Subsection 2d requires that any&#xA;application-supplied function or table used by this function must&#xA;be optional: if the application does not supply it, the square&#xA;root function must still compute square roots.)&#xA;&#xA;These requirements apply to the modified work as a whole.  If&#xA;identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Library,&#xA;and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in&#xA;themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those&#xA;sections when you distribute them as separate works.  But when you&#xA;distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based&#xA;on the Library, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of&#xA;this License, whose permissions for other licensees extend to the&#xA;entire whole, and thus to each and every part regardless of who wrote&#xA;it.&#xA;&#xA;Thus, it is not the intent of this section to claim rights or contest&#xA;your rights to work written entirely by you; rather, the intent is to&#xA;exercise the right to control the distribution of derivative or&#xA;collective works based on the Library.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, mere aggregation of another work not based on the Library&#xA;with the Library (or with a work based on the Library) on a volume of&#xA;a storage or distribution medium does not bring the other work under&#xA;the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;3. You may opt to apply the terms of the ordinary GNU General Public&#xA;License instead of this License to a given copy of the Library.  To do&#xA;this, you must alter all the notices that refer to this License, so&#xA;that they refer to the ordinary GNU General Public License, version 2,&#xA;instead of to this License.  (If a newer version than version 2 of the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License has appeared, then you can specify&#xA;that version instead if you wish.)  Do not make any other change in&#xA;these notices.&#xA;&#xA;Once this change is made in a given copy, it is irreversible for&#xA;that copy, so the ordinary GNU General Public License applies to all&#xA;subsequent copies and derivative works made from that copy.&#xA;&#xA;This option is useful when you wish to copy part of the code of&#xA;the Library into a program that is not a library.&#xA;&#xA;4. You may copy and distribute the Library (or a portion or&#xA;derivative of it, under Section 2) in object code or executable form&#xA;under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above provided that you accompany&#xA;it with the complete corresponding machine-readable source code, which&#xA;must be distributed under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above on a&#xA;medium customarily used for software interchange.&#xA;&#xA;If distribution of object code is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, then offering equivalent access to copy the&#xA;source code from the same place satisfies the requirement to&#xA;distribute the source code, even though third parties are not&#xA;compelled to copy the source along with the object code.&#xA;&#xA;5. A program that contains no derivative of any portion of the&#xA;Library, but is designed to work with the Library by being compiled or&#xA;linked with it, is called a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot;.  Such a&#xA;work, in isolation, is not a derivative work of the Library, and&#xA;therefore falls outside the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;However, linking a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library&#xA;creates an executable that is a derivative of the Library (because it&#xA;contains portions of the Library), rather than a &quot;work that uses the&#xA;library&quot;.  The executable is therefore covered by this License.&#xA;Section 6 states terms for distribution of such executables.&#xA;&#xA;When a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; uses material from a header file&#xA;that is part of the Library, the object code for the work may be a&#xA;derivative work of the Library even though the source code is not.&#xA;Whether this is true is especially significant if the work can be&#xA;linked without the Library, or if the work is itself a library.  The&#xA;threshold for this to be true is not precisely defined by law.&#xA;&#xA;If such an object file uses only numerical parameters, data&#xA;structure layouts and accessors, and small macros and small inline&#xA;functions (ten lines or less in length), then the use of the object&#xA;file is unrestricted, regardless of whether it is legally a derivative&#xA;work.  (Executables containing this object code plus portions of the&#xA;Library will still fall under Section 6.)&#xA;&#xA;Otherwise, if the work is a derivative of the Library, you may&#xA;distribute the object code for the work under the terms of Section 6.&#xA;Any executables containing that work also fall under Section 6,&#xA;whether or not they are linked directly with the Library itself.&#xA;&#xA;6. As an exception to the Sections above, you may also combine or&#xA;link a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library to produce a&#xA;work containing portions of the Library, and distribute that work&#xA;under terms of your choice, provided that the terms permit&#xA;modification of the work for the customer&apos;s own use and reverse&#xA;engineering for debugging such modifications.&#xA;&#xA;You must give prominent notice with each copy of the work that the&#xA;Library is used in it and that the Library and its use are covered by&#xA;this License.  You must supply a copy of this License.  If the work&#xA;during execution displays copyright notices, you must include the&#xA;copyright notice for the Library among them, as well as a reference&#xA;directing the user to the copy of this License.  Also, you must do one&#xA;of these things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the work with the complete corresponding&#xA;machine-readable source code for the Library including whatever&#xA;changes were used in the work (which must be distributed under&#xA;Sections 1 and 2 above); and, if the work is an executable linked&#xA;with the Library, with the complete machine-readable &quot;work that&#xA;uses the Library&quot;, as object code and/or source code, so that the&#xA;user can modify the Library and then relink to produce a modified&#xA;executable containing the modified Library.  (It is understood&#xA;that the user who changes the contents of definitions files in the&#xA;Library will not necessarily be able to recompile the application&#xA;to use the modified definitions.)&#xA;&#xA;b) Use a suitable shared library mechanism for linking with the&#xA;Library.  A suitable mechanism is one that (1) uses at run time a&#xA;copy of the library already present on the user&apos;s computer system,&#xA;rather than copying library functions into the executable, and (2)&#xA;will operate properly with a modified version of the library, if&#xA;the user installs one, as long as the modified version is&#xA;interface-compatible with the version that the work was made with.&#xA;&#xA;c) Accompany the work with a written offer, valid for at&#xA;least three years, to give the same user the materials&#xA;specified in Subsection 6a, above, for a charge no more&#xA;than the cost of performing this distribution.&#xA;&#xA;d) If distribution of the work is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, offer equivalent access to copy the above&#xA;specified materials from the same place.&#xA;&#xA;e) Verify that the user has already received a copy of these&#xA;materials or that you have already sent this user a copy.&#xA;&#xA;For an executable, the required form of the &quot;work that uses the&#xA;Library&quot; must include any data and utility programs needed for&#xA;reproducing the executable from it.  However, as a special exception,&#xA;the materials to be distributed need not include anything that is&#xA;normally distributed (in either source or binary form) with the major&#xA;components (compiler, kernel, and so on) of the operating system on&#xA;which the executable runs, unless that component itself accompanies&#xA;the executable.&#xA;&#xA;It may happen that this requirement contradicts the license&#xA;restrictions of other proprietary libraries that do not normally&#xA;accompany the operating system.  Such a contradiction means you cannot&#xA;use both them and the Library together in an executable that you&#xA;distribute.&#xA;&#xA;7. You may place library facilities that are a work based on the&#xA;Library side-by-side in a single library together with other library&#xA;facilities not covered by this License, and distribute such a combined&#xA;library, provided that the separate distribution of the work based on&#xA;the Library and of the other library facilities is otherwise&#xA;permitted, and provided that you do these two things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the combined library with a copy of the same work&#xA;based on the Library, uncombined with any other library&#xA;facilities.  This must be distributed under the terms of the&#xA;Sections above.&#xA;&#xA;b) Give prominent notice with the combined library of the fact&#xA;that part of it is a work based on the Library, and explaining&#xA;where to find the accompanying uncombined form of the same work.&#xA;&#xA;8. You may not copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or distribute&#xA;the Library except as expressly provided under this License.  Any&#xA;attempt otherwise to copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or&#xA;distribute the Library is void, and will automatically terminate your&#xA;rights under this License.  However, parties who have received copies,&#xA;or rights, from you under this License will not have their licenses&#xA;terminated so long as such parties remain in full compliance.&#xA;&#xA;9. You are not required to accept this License, since you have not&#xA;signed it.  However, nothing else grants you permission to modify or&#xA;distribute the Library or its derivative works.  These actions are&#xA;prohibited by law if you do not accept this License.  Therefore, by&#xA;modifying or distributing the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), you indicate your acceptance of this License to do so, and&#xA;all its terms and conditions for copying, distributing or modifying&#xA;the Library or works based on it.&#xA;&#xA;10. Each time you redistribute the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), the recipient automatically receives a license from the&#xA;original licensor to copy, distribute, link with or modify the Library&#xA;subject to these terms and conditions.  You may not impose any further&#xA;restrictions on the recipients&apos; exercise of the rights granted herein.&#xA;You are not responsible for enforcing compliance by third parties with&#xA;this License.&#xA;&#xA;11. If, as a consequence of a court judgment or allegation of patent&#xA;infringement or for any other reason (not limited to patent issues),&#xA;conditions are imposed on you (whether by court order, agreement or&#xA;otherwise) that contradict the conditions of this License, they do not&#xA;excuse you from the conditions of this License.  If you cannot&#xA;distribute so as to satisfy simultaneously your obligations under this&#xA;License and any other pertinent obligations, then as a consequence you&#xA;may not distribute the Library at all.  For example, if a patent&#xA;license would not permit royalty-free redistribution of the Library by&#xA;all those who receive copies directly or indirectly through you, then&#xA;the only way you could satisfy both it and this License would be to&#xA;refrain entirely from distribution of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;If any portion of this section is held invalid or unenforceable under any&#xA;particular circumstance, the balance of the section is intended to apply,&#xA;and the section as a whole is intended to apply in other circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;It is not the purpose of this section to induce you to infringe any&#xA;patents or other property right claims or to contest validity of any&#xA;such claims; this section has the sole purpose of protecting the&#xA;integrity of the free software distribution system which is&#xA;implemented by public license practices.  Many people have made&#xA;generous contributions to the wide range of software distributed&#xA;through that system in reliance on consistent application of that&#xA;system; it is up to the author/donor to decide if he or she is willing&#xA;to distribute software through any other system and a licensee cannot&#xA;impose that choice.&#xA;&#xA;This section is intended to make thoroughly clear what is believed to&#xA;be a consequence of the rest of this License.&#xA;&#xA;12. If the distribution and/or use of the Library is restricted in&#xA;certain countries either by patents or by copyrighted interfaces, the&#xA;original copyright holder who places the Library under this License may add&#xA;an explicit geographical distribution limitation excluding those countries,&#xA;so that distribution is permitted only in or among countries not thus&#xA;excluded.  In such case, this License incorporates the limitation as if&#xA;written in the body of this License.&#xA;&#xA;13. The Free Software Foundation may publish revised and/or new&#xA;versions of the Lesser General Public License from time to time.&#xA;Such new versions will be similar in spirit to the present version,&#xA;but may differ in detail to address new problems or concerns.&#xA;&#xA;Each version is given a distinguishing version number.  If the Library&#xA;specifies a version number of this License which applies to it and&#xA;&quot;any later version&quot;, you have the option of following the terms and&#xA;conditions either of that version or of any later version published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.  If the Library does not specify a&#xA;license version number, you may choose any version ever published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.&#xA;&#xA;14. If you wish to incorporate parts of the Library into other free&#xA;programs whose distribution conditions are incompatible with these,&#xA;write to the author to ask for permission.  For software which is&#xA;copyrighted by the Free Software Foundation, write to the Free&#xA;Software Foundation; we sometimes make exceptions for this.  Our&#xA;decision will be guided by the two goals of preserving the free status&#xA;of all derivatives of our free software and of promoting the sharing&#xA;and reuse of software generally.&#xA;&#xA;NO WARRANTY&#xA;&#xA;15. BECAUSE THE LIBRARY IS LICENSED FREE OF CHARGE, THERE IS NO&#xA;WARRANTY FOR THE LIBRARY, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW.&#xA;EXCEPT WHEN OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND/OR&#xA;OTHER PARTIES PROVIDE THE LIBRARY &quot;AS IS&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY&#xA;KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE&#xA;IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR&#xA;PURPOSE.  THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE&#xA;LIBRARY IS WITH YOU.  SHOULD THE LIBRARY PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME&#xA;THE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.&#xA;&#xA;16. IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN&#xA;WRITING WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MAY MODIFY&#xA;AND/OR REDISTRIBUTE THE LIBRARY AS PERMITTED ABOVE, BE LIABLE TO YOU&#xA;FOR DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR&#xA;CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE&#xA;LIBRARY (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF DATA OR DATA BEING&#xA;RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY YOU OR THIRD PARTIES OR A&#xA;FAILURE OF THE LIBRARY TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER SOFTWARE), EVEN IF&#xA;SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH&#xA;DAMAGES.&#xA;&#xA;END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS&#xA;&#xA;How to Apply These Terms to Your New Libraries&#xA;&#xA;If you develop a new library, and you want it to be of the greatest&#xA;possible use to the public, we recommend making it free software that&#xA;everyone can redistribute and change.  You can do so by permitting&#xA;redistribution under these terms (or, alternatively, under the terms of the&#xA;ordinary General Public License).&#xA;&#xA;To apply these terms, attach the following notices to the library.  It is&#xA;safest to attach them to the start of each source file to most effectively&#xA;convey the exclusion of warranty; and each file should have at least the&#xA;&quot;copyright&quot; line and a pointer to where the full notice is found.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;one line to give the library&apos;s name and a brief idea of what it does.&gt;&#xA;Copyright (C) &lt;year&gt;  &lt;name of author&gt;&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;&#xA;Also add information on how to contact you by electronic and paper mail.&#xA;&#xA;You should also get your employer (if you work as a programmer) or your&#xA;school, if any, to sign a &quot;copyright disclaimer&quot; for the library, if&#xA;necessary.  Here is a sample; alter the names:&#xA;&#xA;Yoyodyne, Inc., hereby disclaims all copyright interest in the&#xA;library `Frob&apos; (a library for tweaking knobs) written by James Random Hacker.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;signature of Ty Coon&gt;, 1 April 1990&#xA;Ty Coon, President of Vice&#xA;&#xA;That&apos;s all there is to it!'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.jar' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='feature' version='1.0.0'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.update.feature' name='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs'/>
      </provides>
      <filter>
        (org.eclipse.update.install.features=true)
      </filter>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='org.eclipse.update.feature' id='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='1'>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
      <licenses size='1'>
        <license uri='%25licenseURL' url='%25licenseURL'>
          %license
        </license>
      </licenses>
      <copyright uri='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html' url='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html'>
        %copyright
      </copyright>
    </unit>
    <unit id='http://rxtx.qbang.org/eclipse/site.xml.RXTX 2.1-7r4' version='1.0.0.7837QcJa5vE7MnhE77YA7AU3SWUlbntVZAnlDoIGojcQd'>
      <properties size='3'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='RXTX 2.1-7r4'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='RXTX 2.1-7r2 plus disable-version-output (RXTXCommDriver v1.16.2.57, RXTX bug 71), fix-deadlock (CommPortIdentifier, RXTX bug 83), disable-lockfiles, sparc-sun-solaris2.7 support (RXTX bug 73)'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.type.category' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='1'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='http://rxtx.qbang.org/eclipse/site.xml.RXTX 2.1-7r4' version='1.0.0.7837QcJa5vE7MnhE77YA7AU3SWUlbntVZAnlDoIGojcQd'/>
      </provides>
      <requires size='2'>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.group' range='[2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg,2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg]'/>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.group' range='[2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf,2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf]'/>
      </requires>
      <touchpoint id='null' version='0.0.0'/>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.group' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.group' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='10'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='%featureName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='%description'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description.url' value='http://www.rxtx.org'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.provider' value='%providerName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.type.group' value='true'/>
        <property name='df_LT.featureName' value='RXTX End-User Runtime'/>
        <property name='df_LT.providerName' value='RXTX.org'/>
        <property name='df_LT.description' value='RXTX is a library to access serial ports from Java. '/>
        <property name='df_LT.copyright' value='Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.'/>
        <property name='df_LT.license' value='RXTX License v 2.1 - LGPL v 2.1 + Linking Over Controlled Interface.&#xA;RXTX is a native interface to serial ports in java.&#xA;&#xA;Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.&#xA;&#xA;A copy of the LGPL v 2.1 may be found at&#xA;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl.txt on March 4th 2007.  A copy is&#xA;included below for your convenience.&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;An executable that contains no derivative of any portion of RXTX, but&#xA;is designed to work with RXTX by being dynamically linked with it,&#xA;is considered a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; subject to the terms and&#xA;conditions of the GNU Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;The following has been added to the RXTX License to remove&#xA;any confusion about linking to RXTX.   We want to allow in part what&#xA;section 5, paragraph 2 of the LGPL does not permit in the special&#xA;case of linking over a controlled interface.  The intent is to add a&#xA;Java Specification Request or standards body defined interface in the&#xA;future as another exception but one is not currently available.&#xA;&#xA;http://www.fsf.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#LinkingOverControlledInterface&#xA;&#xA;As a special exception, the copyright holders of RXTX give you&#xA;permission to link RXTX with independent modules that communicate with&#xA;RXTX solely through the Sun Microsytems CommAPI interface version 2,&#xA;regardless of the license terms of these independent modules, and to copy&#xA;and distribute the resulting combined work under terms of your choice,&#xA;provided that every copy of the combined work is accompanied by a complete&#xA;copy of the source code of RXTX (the version of RXTX used to produce the&#xA;combined work), being distributed under the terms of the GNU Lesser General&#xA;Public License plus this exception.  An independent module is a&#xA;module which is not derived from or based on RXTX.&#xA;&#xA;Note that people who make modified versions of RXTX are not obligated&#xA;to grant this special exception for their modified versions; it is&#xA;their choice whether to do so.  The GNU Lesser General Public License&#xA;gives permission to release a modified version without this exception; this&#xA;exception also makes it possible to release a modified version which&#xA;carries forward this exception.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA&#xA;All trademarks belong to their respective owners.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;Version 2.1, February 1999&#xA;&#xA;Copyright (C) 1991, 1999 Free Software Foundation, Inc.&#xA;51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies&#xA;of this license document, but changing it is not allowed.&#xA;&#xA;[This is the first released version of the Lesser GPL.  It also counts&#xA;as the successor of the GNU Library Public License, version 2, hence&#xA;the version number 2.1.]&#xA;&#xA;Preamble&#xA;&#xA;The licenses for most software are designed to take away your&#xA;freedom to share and change it.  By contrast, the GNU General Public&#xA;Licenses are intended to guarantee your freedom to share and change&#xA;free software--to make sure the software is free for all its users.&#xA;&#xA;This license, the Lesser General Public License, applies to some&#xA;specially designated software packages--typically libraries--of the&#xA;Free Software Foundation and other authors who decide to use it.  You&#xA;can use it too, but we suggest you first think carefully about whether&#xA;this license or the ordinary General Public License is the better&#xA;strategy to use in any particular case, based on the explanations below.&#xA;&#xA;When we speak of free software, we are referring to freedom of use,&#xA;not price.  Our General Public Licenses are designed to make sure that&#xA;you have the freedom to distribute copies of free software (and charge&#xA;for this service if you wish); that you receive source code or can get&#xA;it if you want it; that you can change the software and use pieces of&#xA;it in new free programs; and that you are informed that you can do&#xA;these things.&#xA;&#xA;To protect your rights, we need to make restrictions that forbid&#xA;distributors to deny you these rights or to ask you to surrender these&#xA;rights.  These restrictions translate to certain responsibilities for&#xA;you if you distribute copies of the library or if you modify it.&#xA;&#xA;For example, if you distribute copies of the library, whether gratis&#xA;or for a fee, you must give the recipients all the rights that we gave&#xA;you.  You must make sure that they, too, receive or can get the source&#xA;code.  If you link other code with the library, you must provide&#xA;complete object files to the recipients, so that they can relink them&#xA;with the library after making changes to the library and recompiling&#xA;it.  And you must show them these terms so they know their rights.&#xA;&#xA;We protect your rights with a two-step method: (1) we copyright the&#xA;library, and (2) we offer you this license, which gives you legal&#xA;permission to copy, distribute and/or modify the library.&#xA;&#xA;To protect each distributor, we want to make it very clear that&#xA;there is no warranty for the free library.  Also, if the library is&#xA;modified by someone else and passed on, the recipients should know&#xA;that what they have is not the original version, so that the original&#xA;author&apos;s reputation will not be affected by problems that might be&#xA;introduced by others.&#xA;&#xA;Finally, software patents pose a constant threat to the existence of&#xA;any free program.  We wish to make sure that a company cannot&#xA;effectively restrict the users of a free program by obtaining a&#xA;restrictive license from a patent holder.  Therefore, we insist that&#xA;any patent license obtained for a version of the library must be&#xA;consistent with the full freedom of use specified in this license.&#xA;&#xA;Most GNU software, including some libraries, is covered by the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License.  This license, the GNU Lesser&#xA;General Public License, applies to certain designated libraries, and&#xA;is quite different from the ordinary General Public License.  We use&#xA;this license for certain libraries in order to permit linking those&#xA;libraries into non-free programs.&#xA;&#xA;When a program is linked with a library, whether statically or using&#xA;a shared library, the combination of the two is legally speaking a&#xA;combined work, a derivative of the original library.  The ordinary&#xA;General Public License therefore permits such linking only if the&#xA;entire combination fits its criteria of freedom.  The Lesser General&#xA;Public License permits more lax criteria for linking other code with&#xA;the library.&#xA;&#xA;We call this license the &quot;Lesser&quot; General Public License because it&#xA;does Less to protect the user&apos;s freedom than the ordinary General&#xA;Public License.  It also provides other free software developers Less&#xA;of an advantage over competing non-free programs.  These disadvantages&#xA;are the reason we use the ordinary General Public License for many&#xA;libraries.  However, the Lesser license provides advantages in certain&#xA;special circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;For example, on rare occasions, there may be a special need to&#xA;encourage the widest possible use of a certain library, so that it becomes&#xA;a de-facto standard.  To achieve this, non-free programs must be&#xA;allowed to use the library.  A more frequent case is that a free&#xA;library does the same job as widely used non-free libraries.  In this&#xA;case, there is little to gain by limiting the free library to free&#xA;software only, so we use the Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;In other cases, permission to use a particular library in non-free&#xA;programs enables a greater number of people to use a large body of&#xA;free software.  For example, permission to use the GNU C Library in&#xA;non-free programs enables many more people to use the whole GNU&#xA;operating system, as well as its variant, the GNU/Linux operating&#xA;system.&#xA;&#xA;Although the Lesser General Public License is Less protective of the&#xA;users&apos; freedom, it does ensure that the user of a program that is&#xA;linked with the Library has the freedom and the wherewithal to run&#xA;that program using a modified version of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;The precise terms and conditions for copying, distribution and&#xA;modification follow.  Pay close attention to the difference between a&#xA;&quot;work based on the library&quot; and a &quot;work that uses the library&quot;.  The&#xA;former contains code derived from the library, whereas the latter must&#xA;be combined with the library in order to run.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR COPYING, DISTRIBUTION AND MODIFICATION&#xA;&#xA;0. This License Agreement applies to any software library or other&#xA;program which contains a notice placed by the copyright holder or&#xA;other authorized party saying it may be distributed under the terms of&#xA;this Lesser General Public License (also called &quot;this License&quot;).&#xA;Each licensee is addressed as &quot;you&quot;.&#xA;&#xA;A &quot;library&quot; means a collection of software functions and/or data&#xA;prepared so as to be conveniently linked with application programs&#xA;(which use some of those functions and data) to form executables.&#xA;&#xA;The &quot;Library&quot;, below, refers to any such software library or work&#xA;which has been distributed under these terms.  A &quot;work based on the&#xA;Library&quot; means either the Library or any derivative work under&#xA;copyright law: that is to say, a work containing the Library or a&#xA;portion of it, either verbatim or with modifications and/or translated&#xA;straightforwardly into another language.  (Hereinafter, translation is&#xA;included without limitation in the term &quot;modification&quot;.)&#xA;&#xA;&quot;Source code&quot; for a work means the preferred form of the work for&#xA;making modifications to it.  For a library, complete source code means&#xA;all the source code for all modules it contains, plus any associated&#xA;interface definition files, plus the scripts used to control compilation&#xA;and installation of the library.&#xA;&#xA;Activities other than copying, distribution and modification are not&#xA;covered by this License; they are outside its scope.  The act of&#xA;running a program using the Library is not restricted, and output from&#xA;such a program is covered only if its contents constitute a work based&#xA;on the Library (independent of the use of the Library in a tool for&#xA;writing it).  Whether that is true depends on what the Library does&#xA;and what the program that uses the Library does.&#xA;&#xA;1. You may copy and distribute verbatim copies of the Library&apos;s&#xA;complete source code as you receive it, in any medium, provided that&#xA;you conspicuously and appropriately publish on each copy an&#xA;appropriate copyright notice and disclaimer of warranty; keep intact&#xA;all the notices that refer to this License and to the absence of any&#xA;warranty; and distribute a copy of this License along with the&#xA;Library.&#xA;&#xA;You may charge a fee for the physical act of transferring a copy,&#xA;and you may at your option offer warranty protection in exchange for a&#xA;fee.&#xA;&#xA;2. You may modify your copy or copies of the Library or any portion&#xA;of it, thus forming a work based on the Library, and copy and&#xA;distribute such modifications or work under the terms of Section 1&#xA;above, provided that you also meet all of these conditions:&#xA;&#xA;a) The modified work must itself be a software library.&#xA;&#xA;b) You must cause the files modified to carry prominent notices&#xA;stating that you changed the files and the date of any change.&#xA;&#xA;c) You must cause the whole of the work to be licensed at no&#xA;charge to all third parties under the terms of this License.&#xA;&#xA;d) If a facility in the modified Library refers to a function or a&#xA;table of data to be supplied by an application program that uses&#xA;the facility, other than as an argument passed when the facility&#xA;is invoked, then you must make a good faith effort to ensure that,&#xA;in the event an application does not supply such function or&#xA;table, the facility still operates, and performs whatever part of&#xA;its purpose remains meaningful.&#xA;&#xA;(For example, a function in a library to compute square roots has&#xA;a purpose that is entirely well-defined independent of the&#xA;application.  Therefore, Subsection 2d requires that any&#xA;application-supplied function or table used by this function must&#xA;be optional: if the application does not supply it, the square&#xA;root function must still compute square roots.)&#xA;&#xA;These requirements apply to the modified work as a whole.  If&#xA;identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Library,&#xA;and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in&#xA;themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those&#xA;sections when you distribute them as separate works.  But when you&#xA;distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based&#xA;on the Library, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of&#xA;this License, whose permissions for other licensees extend to the&#xA;entire whole, and thus to each and every part regardless of who wrote&#xA;it.&#xA;&#xA;Thus, it is not the intent of this section to claim rights or contest&#xA;your rights to work written entirely by you; rather, the intent is to&#xA;exercise the right to control the distribution of derivative or&#xA;collective works based on the Library.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, mere aggregation of another work not based on the Library&#xA;with the Library (or with a work based on the Library) on a volume of&#xA;a storage or distribution medium does not bring the other work under&#xA;the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;3. You may opt to apply the terms of the ordinary GNU General Public&#xA;License instead of this License to a given copy of the Library.  To do&#xA;this, you must alter all the notices that refer to this License, so&#xA;that they refer to the ordinary GNU General Public License, version 2,&#xA;instead of to this License.  (If a newer version than version 2 of the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License has appeared, then you can specify&#xA;that version instead if you wish.)  Do not make any other change in&#xA;these notices.&#xA;&#xA;Once this change is made in a given copy, it is irreversible for&#xA;that copy, so the ordinary GNU General Public License applies to all&#xA;subsequent copies and derivative works made from that copy.&#xA;&#xA;This option is useful when you wish to copy part of the code of&#xA;the Library into a program that is not a library.&#xA;&#xA;4. You may copy and distribute the Library (or a portion or&#xA;derivative of it, under Section 2) in object code or executable form&#xA;under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above provided that you accompany&#xA;it with the complete corresponding machine-readable source code, which&#xA;must be distributed under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above on a&#xA;medium customarily used for software interchange.&#xA;&#xA;If distribution of object code is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, then offering equivalent access to copy the&#xA;source code from the same place satisfies the requirement to&#xA;distribute the source code, even though third parties are not&#xA;compelled to copy the source along with the object code.&#xA;&#xA;5. A program that contains no derivative of any portion of the&#xA;Library, but is designed to work with the Library by being compiled or&#xA;linked with it, is called a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot;.  Such a&#xA;work, in isolation, is not a derivative work of the Library, and&#xA;therefore falls outside the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;However, linking a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library&#xA;creates an executable that is a derivative of the Library (because it&#xA;contains portions of the Library), rather than a &quot;work that uses the&#xA;library&quot;.  The executable is therefore covered by this License.&#xA;Section 6 states terms for distribution of such executables.&#xA;&#xA;When a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; uses material from a header file&#xA;that is part of the Library, the object code for the work may be a&#xA;derivative work of the Library even though the source code is not.&#xA;Whether this is true is especially significant if the work can be&#xA;linked without the Library, or if the work is itself a library.  The&#xA;threshold for this to be true is not precisely defined by law.&#xA;&#xA;If such an object file uses only numerical parameters, data&#xA;structure layouts and accessors, and small macros and small inline&#xA;functions (ten lines or less in length), then the use of the object&#xA;file is unrestricted, regardless of whether it is legally a derivative&#xA;work.  (Executables containing this object code plus portions of the&#xA;Library will still fall under Section 6.)&#xA;&#xA;Otherwise, if the work is a derivative of the Library, you may&#xA;distribute the object code for the work under the terms of Section 6.&#xA;Any executables containing that work also fall under Section 6,&#xA;whether or not they are linked directly with the Library itself.&#xA;&#xA;6. As an exception to the Sections above, you may also combine or&#xA;link a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library to produce a&#xA;work containing portions of the Library, and distribute that work&#xA;under terms of your choice, provided that the terms permit&#xA;modification of the work for the customer&apos;s own use and reverse&#xA;engineering for debugging such modifications.&#xA;&#xA;You must give prominent notice with each copy of the work that the&#xA;Library is used in it and that the Library and its use are covered by&#xA;this License.  You must supply a copy of this License.  If the work&#xA;during execution displays copyright notices, you must include the&#xA;copyright notice for the Library among them, as well as a reference&#xA;directing the user to the copy of this License.  Also, you must do one&#xA;of these things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the work with the complete corresponding&#xA;machine-readable source code for the Library including whatever&#xA;changes were used in the work (which must be distributed under&#xA;Sections 1 and 2 above); and, if the work is an executable linked&#xA;with the Library, with the complete machine-readable &quot;work that&#xA;uses the Library&quot;, as object code and/or source code, so that the&#xA;user can modify the Library and then relink to produce a modified&#xA;executable containing the modified Library.  (It is understood&#xA;that the user who changes the contents of definitions files in the&#xA;Library will not necessarily be able to recompile the application&#xA;to use the modified definitions.)&#xA;&#xA;b) Use a suitable shared library mechanism for linking with the&#xA;Library.  A suitable mechanism is one that (1) uses at run time a&#xA;copy of the library already present on the user&apos;s computer system,&#xA;rather than copying library functions into the executable, and (2)&#xA;will operate properly with a modified version of the library, if&#xA;the user installs one, as long as the modified version is&#xA;interface-compatible with the version that the work was made with.&#xA;&#xA;c) Accompany the work with a written offer, valid for at&#xA;least three years, to give the same user the materials&#xA;specified in Subsection 6a, above, for a charge no more&#xA;than the cost of performing this distribution.&#xA;&#xA;d) If distribution of the work is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, offer equivalent access to copy the above&#xA;specified materials from the same place.&#xA;&#xA;e) Verify that the user has already received a copy of these&#xA;materials or that you have already sent this user a copy.&#xA;&#xA;For an executable, the required form of the &quot;work that uses the&#xA;Library&quot; must include any data and utility programs needed for&#xA;reproducing the executable from it.  However, as a special exception,&#xA;the materials to be distributed need not include anything that is&#xA;normally distributed (in either source or binary form) with the major&#xA;components (compiler, kernel, and so on) of the operating system on&#xA;which the executable runs, unless that component itself accompanies&#xA;the executable.&#xA;&#xA;It may happen that this requirement contradicts the license&#xA;restrictions of other proprietary libraries that do not normally&#xA;accompany the operating system.  Such a contradiction means you cannot&#xA;use both them and the Library together in an executable that you&#xA;distribute.&#xA;&#xA;7. You may place library facilities that are a work based on the&#xA;Library side-by-side in a single library together with other library&#xA;facilities not covered by this License, and distribute such a combined&#xA;library, provided that the separate distribution of the work based on&#xA;the Library and of the other library facilities is otherwise&#xA;permitted, and provided that you do these two things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the combined library with a copy of the same work&#xA;based on the Library, uncombined with any other library&#xA;facilities.  This must be distributed under the terms of the&#xA;Sections above.&#xA;&#xA;b) Give prominent notice with the combined library of the fact&#xA;that part of it is a work based on the Library, and explaining&#xA;where to find the accompanying uncombined form of the same work.&#xA;&#xA;8. You may not copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or distribute&#xA;the Library except as expressly provided under this License.  Any&#xA;attempt otherwise to copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or&#xA;distribute the Library is void, and will automatically terminate your&#xA;rights under this License.  However, parties who have received copies,&#xA;or rights, from you under this License will not have their licenses&#xA;terminated so long as such parties remain in full compliance.&#xA;&#xA;9. You are not required to accept this License, since you have not&#xA;signed it.  However, nothing else grants you permission to modify or&#xA;distribute the Library or its derivative works.  These actions are&#xA;prohibited by law if you do not accept this License.  Therefore, by&#xA;modifying or distributing the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), you indicate your acceptance of this License to do so, and&#xA;all its terms and conditions for copying, distributing or modifying&#xA;the Library or works based on it.&#xA;&#xA;10. Each time you redistribute the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), the recipient automatically receives a license from the&#xA;original licensor to copy, distribute, link with or modify the Library&#xA;subject to these terms and conditions.  You may not impose any further&#xA;restrictions on the recipients&apos; exercise of the rights granted herein.&#xA;You are not responsible for enforcing compliance by third parties with&#xA;this License.&#xA;&#xA;11. If, as a consequence of a court judgment or allegation of patent&#xA;infringement or for any other reason (not limited to patent issues),&#xA;conditions are imposed on you (whether by court order, agreement or&#xA;otherwise) that contradict the conditions of this License, they do not&#xA;excuse you from the conditions of this License.  If you cannot&#xA;distribute so as to satisfy simultaneously your obligations under this&#xA;License and any other pertinent obligations, then as a consequence you&#xA;may not distribute the Library at all.  For example, if a patent&#xA;license would not permit royalty-free redistribution of the Library by&#xA;all those who receive copies directly or indirectly through you, then&#xA;the only way you could satisfy both it and this License would be to&#xA;refrain entirely from distribution of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;If any portion of this section is held invalid or unenforceable under any&#xA;particular circumstance, the balance of the section is intended to apply,&#xA;and the section as a whole is intended to apply in other circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;It is not the purpose of this section to induce you to infringe any&#xA;patents or other property right claims or to contest validity of any&#xA;such claims; this section has the sole purpose of protecting the&#xA;integrity of the free software distribution system which is&#xA;implemented by public license practices.  Many people have made&#xA;generous contributions to the wide range of software distributed&#xA;through that system in reliance on consistent application of that&#xA;system; it is up to the author/donor to decide if he or she is willing&#xA;to distribute software through any other system and a licensee cannot&#xA;impose that choice.&#xA;&#xA;This section is intended to make thoroughly clear what is believed to&#xA;be a consequence of the rest of this License.&#xA;&#xA;12. If the distribution and/or use of the Library is restricted in&#xA;certain countries either by patents or by copyrighted interfaces, the&#xA;original copyright holder who places the Library under this License may add&#xA;an explicit geographical distribution limitation excluding those countries,&#xA;so that distribution is permitted only in or among countries not thus&#xA;excluded.  In such case, this License incorporates the limitation as if&#xA;written in the body of this License.&#xA;&#xA;13. The Free Software Foundation may publish revised and/or new&#xA;versions of the Lesser General Public License from time to time.&#xA;Such new versions will be similar in spirit to the present version,&#xA;but may differ in detail to address new problems or concerns.&#xA;&#xA;Each version is given a distinguishing version number.  If the Library&#xA;specifies a version number of this License which applies to it and&#xA;&quot;any later version&quot;, you have the option of following the terms and&#xA;conditions either of that version or of any later version published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.  If the Library does not specify a&#xA;license version number, you may choose any version ever published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.&#xA;&#xA;14. If you wish to incorporate parts of the Library into other free&#xA;programs whose distribution conditions are incompatible with these,&#xA;write to the author to ask for permission.  For software which is&#xA;copyrighted by the Free Software Foundation, write to the Free&#xA;Software Foundation; we sometimes make exceptions for this.  Our&#xA;decision will be guided by the two goals of preserving the free status&#xA;of all derivatives of our free software and of promoting the sharing&#xA;and reuse of software generally.&#xA;&#xA;NO WARRANTY&#xA;&#xA;15. BECAUSE THE LIBRARY IS LICENSED FREE OF CHARGE, THERE IS NO&#xA;WARRANTY FOR THE LIBRARY, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW.&#xA;EXCEPT WHEN OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND/OR&#xA;OTHER PARTIES PROVIDE THE LIBRARY &quot;AS IS&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY&#xA;KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE&#xA;IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR&#xA;PURPOSE.  THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE&#xA;LIBRARY IS WITH YOU.  SHOULD THE LIBRARY PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME&#xA;THE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.&#xA;&#xA;16. IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN&#xA;WRITING WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MAY MODIFY&#xA;AND/OR REDISTRIBUTE THE LIBRARY AS PERMITTED ABOVE, BE LIABLE TO YOU&#xA;FOR DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR&#xA;CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE&#xA;LIBRARY (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF DATA OR DATA BEING&#xA;RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY YOU OR THIRD PARTIES OR A&#xA;FAILURE OF THE LIBRARY TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER SOFTWARE), EVEN IF&#xA;SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH&#xA;DAMAGES.&#xA;&#xA;END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS&#xA;&#xA;How to Apply These Terms to Your New Libraries&#xA;&#xA;If you develop a new library, and you want it to be of the greatest&#xA;possible use to the public, we recommend making it free software that&#xA;everyone can redistribute and change.  You can do so by permitting&#xA;redistribution under these terms (or, alternatively, under the terms of the&#xA;ordinary General Public License).&#xA;&#xA;To apply these terms, attach the following notices to the library.  It is&#xA;safest to attach them to the start of each source file to most effectively&#xA;convey the exclusion of warranty; and each file should have at least the&#xA;&quot;copyright&quot; line and a pointer to where the full notice is found.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;one line to give the library&apos;s name and a brief idea of what it does.&gt;&#xA;Copyright (C) &lt;year&gt;  &lt;name of author&gt;&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;&#xA;Also add information on how to contact you by electronic and paper mail.&#xA;&#xA;You should also get your employer (if you work as a programmer) or your&#xA;school, if any, to sign a &quot;copyright disclaimer&quot; for the library, if&#xA;necessary.  Here is a sample; alter the names:&#xA;&#xA;Yoyodyne, Inc., hereby disclaims all copyright interest in the&#xA;library `Frob&apos; (a library for tweaking knobs) written by James Random Hacker.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;signature of Ty Coon&gt;, 1 April 1990&#xA;Ty Coon, President of Vice&#xA;&#xA;That&apos;s all there is to it!'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='2'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.group' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.localization' name='df_LT' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <requires size='7'>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070718,2.1.7.3_v20070718]'/>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070717,2.1.7.3_v20070717]'>
          <filter>
            (&amp;(osgi.arch=x86)(osgi.os=linux))
          </filter>
        </required>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070717,2.1.7.3_v20070717]'>
          <filter>
            (&amp;(osgi.arch=x86_64)(osgi.os=linux))
          </filter>
        </required>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070717,2.1.7.3_v20070717]'>
          <filter>
            (osgi.os=macosx)
          </filter>
        </required>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070717,2.1.7.3_v20070717]'>
          <filter>
            (&amp;(osgi.arch=sparc)(osgi.os=solaris))
          </filter>
        </required>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.win32.x86' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070717,2.1.7.3_v20070717]'>
          <filter>
            (&amp;(osgi.arch=x86)(osgi.os=win32))
          </filter>
        </required>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.jar' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr,2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr]'>
          <filter>
            (org.eclipse.update.install.features=true)
          </filter>
        </required>
      </requires>
      <touchpoint id='null' version='0.0.0'/>
      <licenses size='1'>
        <license uri='%25licenseURL' url='%25licenseURL'>
          %license
        </license>
      </licenses>
      <copyright uri='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html' url='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html'>
        %copyright
      </copyright>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.jar' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr'>
      <properties size='10'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='%featureName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='%description'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description.url' value='http://www.rxtx.org'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.provider' value='%providerName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.update.feature.plugin' value='gnu.io.rxtx'/>
        <property name='df_LT.featureName' value='RXTX End-User Runtime'/>
        <property name='df_LT.providerName' value='RXTX.org'/>
        <property name='df_LT.description' value='RXTX is a library to access serial ports from Java. '/>
        <property name='df_LT.copyright' value='Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.'/>
        <property name='df_LT.license' value='RXTX License v 2.1 - LGPL v 2.1 + Linking Over Controlled Interface.&#xA;RXTX is a native interface to serial ports in java.&#xA;&#xA;Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.&#xA;&#xA;A copy of the LGPL v 2.1 may be found at&#xA;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl.txt on March 4th 2007.  A copy is&#xA;included below for your convenience.&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;An executable that contains no derivative of any portion of RXTX, but&#xA;is designed to work with RXTX by being dynamically linked with it,&#xA;is considered a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; subject to the terms and&#xA;conditions of the GNU Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;The following has been added to the RXTX License to remove&#xA;any confusion about linking to RXTX.   We want to allow in part what&#xA;section 5, paragraph 2 of the LGPL does not permit in the special&#xA;case of linking over a controlled interface.  The intent is to add a&#xA;Java Specification Request or standards body defined interface in the&#xA;future as another exception but one is not currently available.&#xA;&#xA;http://www.fsf.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#LinkingOverControlledInterface&#xA;&#xA;As a special exception, the copyright holders of RXTX give you&#xA;permission to link RXTX with independent modules that communicate with&#xA;RXTX solely through the Sun Microsytems CommAPI interface version 2,&#xA;regardless of the license terms of these independent modules, and to copy&#xA;and distribute the resulting combined work under terms of your choice,&#xA;provided that every copy of the combined work is accompanied by a complete&#xA;copy of the source code of RXTX (the version of RXTX used to produce the&#xA;combined work), being distributed under the terms of the GNU Lesser General&#xA;Public License plus this exception.  An independent module is a&#xA;module which is not derived from or based on RXTX.&#xA;&#xA;Note that people who make modified versions of RXTX are not obligated&#xA;to grant this special exception for their modified versions; it is&#xA;their choice whether to do so.  The GNU Lesser General Public License&#xA;gives permission to release a modified version without this exception; this&#xA;exception also makes it possible to release a modified version which&#xA;carries forward this exception.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA&#xA;All trademarks belong to their respective owners.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;Version 2.1, February 1999&#xA;&#xA;Copyright (C) 1991, 1999 Free Software Foundation, Inc.&#xA;51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies&#xA;of this license document, but changing it is not allowed.&#xA;&#xA;[This is the first released version of the Lesser GPL.  It also counts&#xA;as the successor of the GNU Library Public License, version 2, hence&#xA;the version number 2.1.]&#xA;&#xA;Preamble&#xA;&#xA;The licenses for most software are designed to take away your&#xA;freedom to share and change it.  By contrast, the GNU General Public&#xA;Licenses are intended to guarantee your freedom to share and change&#xA;free software--to make sure the software is free for all its users.&#xA;&#xA;This license, the Lesser General Public License, applies to some&#xA;specially designated software packages--typically libraries--of the&#xA;Free Software Foundation and other authors who decide to use it.  You&#xA;can use it too, but we suggest you first think carefully about whether&#xA;this license or the ordinary General Public License is the better&#xA;strategy to use in any particular case, based on the explanations below.&#xA;&#xA;When we speak of free software, we are referring to freedom of use,&#xA;not price.  Our General Public Licenses are designed to make sure that&#xA;you have the freedom to distribute copies of free software (and charge&#xA;for this service if you wish); that you receive source code or can get&#xA;it if you want it; that you can change the software and use pieces of&#xA;it in new free programs; and that you are informed that you can do&#xA;these things.&#xA;&#xA;To protect your rights, we need to make restrictions that forbid&#xA;distributors to deny you these rights or to ask you to surrender these&#xA;rights.  These restrictions translate to certain responsibilities for&#xA;you if you distribute copies of the library or if you modify it.&#xA;&#xA;For example, if you distribute copies of the library, whether gratis&#xA;or for a fee, you must give the recipients all the rights that we gave&#xA;you.  You must make sure that they, too, receive or can get the source&#xA;code.  If you link other code with the library, you must provide&#xA;complete object files to the recipients, so that they can relink them&#xA;with the library after making changes to the library and recompiling&#xA;it.  And you must show them these terms so they know their rights.&#xA;&#xA;We protect your rights with a two-step method: (1) we copyright the&#xA;library, and (2) we offer you this license, which gives you legal&#xA;permission to copy, distribute and/or modify the library.&#xA;&#xA;To protect each distributor, we want to make it very clear that&#xA;there is no warranty for the free library.  Also, if the library is&#xA;modified by someone else and passed on, the recipients should know&#xA;that what they have is not the original version, so that the original&#xA;author&apos;s reputation will not be affected by problems that might be&#xA;introduced by others.&#xA;&#xA;Finally, software patents pose a constant threat to the existence of&#xA;any free program.  We wish to make sure that a company cannot&#xA;effectively restrict the users of a free program by obtaining a&#xA;restrictive license from a patent holder.  Therefore, we insist that&#xA;any patent license obtained for a version of the library must be&#xA;consistent with the full freedom of use specified in this license.&#xA;&#xA;Most GNU software, including some libraries, is covered by the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License.  This license, the GNU Lesser&#xA;General Public License, applies to certain designated libraries, and&#xA;is quite different from the ordinary General Public License.  We use&#xA;this license for certain libraries in order to permit linking those&#xA;libraries into non-free programs.&#xA;&#xA;When a program is linked with a library, whether statically or using&#xA;a shared library, the combination of the two is legally speaking a&#xA;combined work, a derivative of the original library.  The ordinary&#xA;General Public License therefore permits such linking only if the&#xA;entire combination fits its criteria of freedom.  The Lesser General&#xA;Public License permits more lax criteria for linking other code with&#xA;the library.&#xA;&#xA;We call this license the &quot;Lesser&quot; General Public License because it&#xA;does Less to protect the user&apos;s freedom than the ordinary General&#xA;Public License.  It also provides other free software developers Less&#xA;of an advantage over competing non-free programs.  These disadvantages&#xA;are the reason we use the ordinary General Public License for many&#xA;libraries.  However, the Lesser license provides advantages in certain&#xA;special circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;For example, on rare occasions, there may be a special need to&#xA;encourage the widest possible use of a certain library, so that it becomes&#xA;a de-facto standard.  To achieve this, non-free programs must be&#xA;allowed to use the library.  A more frequent case is that a free&#xA;library does the same job as widely used non-free libraries.  In this&#xA;case, there is little to gain by limiting the free library to free&#xA;software only, so we use the Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;In other cases, permission to use a particular library in non-free&#xA;programs enables a greater number of people to use a large body of&#xA;free software.  For example, permission to use the GNU C Library in&#xA;non-free programs enables many more people to use the whole GNU&#xA;operating system, as well as its variant, the GNU/Linux operating&#xA;system.&#xA;&#xA;Although the Lesser General Public License is Less protective of the&#xA;users&apos; freedom, it does ensure that the user of a program that is&#xA;linked with the Library has the freedom and the wherewithal to run&#xA;that program using a modified version of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;The precise terms and conditions for copying, distribution and&#xA;modification follow.  Pay close attention to the difference between a&#xA;&quot;work based on the library&quot; and a &quot;work that uses the library&quot;.  The&#xA;former contains code derived from the library, whereas the latter must&#xA;be combined with the library in order to run.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR COPYING, DISTRIBUTION AND MODIFICATION&#xA;&#xA;0. This License Agreement applies to any software library or other&#xA;program which contains a notice placed by the copyright holder or&#xA;other authorized party saying it may be distributed under the terms of&#xA;this Lesser General Public License (also called &quot;this License&quot;).&#xA;Each licensee is addressed as &quot;you&quot;.&#xA;&#xA;A &quot;library&quot; means a collection of software functions and/or data&#xA;prepared so as to be conveniently linked with application programs&#xA;(which use some of those functions and data) to form executables.&#xA;&#xA;The &quot;Library&quot;, below, refers to any such software library or work&#xA;which has been distributed under these terms.  A &quot;work based on the&#xA;Library&quot; means either the Library or any derivative work under&#xA;copyright law: that is to say, a work containing the Library or a&#xA;portion of it, either verbatim or with modifications and/or translated&#xA;straightforwardly into another language.  (Hereinafter, translation is&#xA;included without limitation in the term &quot;modification&quot;.)&#xA;&#xA;&quot;Source code&quot; for a work means the preferred form of the work for&#xA;making modifications to it.  For a library, complete source code means&#xA;all the source code for all modules it contains, plus any associated&#xA;interface definition files, plus the scripts used to control compilation&#xA;and installation of the library.&#xA;&#xA;Activities other than copying, distribution and modification are not&#xA;covered by this License; they are outside its scope.  The act of&#xA;running a program using the Library is not restricted, and output from&#xA;such a program is covered only if its contents constitute a work based&#xA;on the Library (independent of the use of the Library in a tool for&#xA;writing it).  Whether that is true depends on what the Library does&#xA;and what the program that uses the Library does.&#xA;&#xA;1. You may copy and distribute verbatim copies of the Library&apos;s&#xA;complete source code as you receive it, in any medium, provided that&#xA;you conspicuously and appropriately publish on each copy an&#xA;appropriate copyright notice and disclaimer of warranty; keep intact&#xA;all the notices that refer to this License and to the absence of any&#xA;warranty; and distribute a copy of this License along with the&#xA;Library.&#xA;&#xA;You may charge a fee for the physical act of transferring a copy,&#xA;and you may at your option offer warranty protection in exchange for a&#xA;fee.&#xA;&#xA;2. You may modify your copy or copies of the Library or any portion&#xA;of it, thus forming a work based on the Library, and copy and&#xA;distribute such modifications or work under the terms of Section 1&#xA;above, provided that you also meet all of these conditions:&#xA;&#xA;a) The modified work must itself be a software library.&#xA;&#xA;b) You must cause the files modified to carry prominent notices&#xA;stating that you changed the files and the date of any change.&#xA;&#xA;c) You must cause the whole of the work to be licensed at no&#xA;charge to all third parties under the terms of this License.&#xA;&#xA;d) If a facility in the modified Library refers to a function or a&#xA;table of data to be supplied by an application program that uses&#xA;the facility, other than as an argument passed when the facility&#xA;is invoked, then you must make a good faith effort to ensure that,&#xA;in the event an application does not supply such function or&#xA;table, the facility still operates, and performs whatever part of&#xA;its purpose remains meaningful.&#xA;&#xA;(For example, a function in a library to compute square roots has&#xA;a purpose that is entirely well-defined independent of the&#xA;application.  Therefore, Subsection 2d requires that any&#xA;application-supplied function or table used by this function must&#xA;be optional: if the application does not supply it, the square&#xA;root function must still compute square roots.)&#xA;&#xA;These requirements apply to the modified work as a whole.  If&#xA;identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Library,&#xA;and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in&#xA;themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those&#xA;sections when you distribute them as separate works.  But when you&#xA;distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based&#xA;on the Library, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of&#xA;this License, whose permissions for other licensees extend to the&#xA;entire whole, and thus to each and every part regardless of who wrote&#xA;it.&#xA;&#xA;Thus, it is not the intent of this section to claim rights or contest&#xA;your rights to work written entirely by you; rather, the intent is to&#xA;exercise the right to control the distribution of derivative or&#xA;collective works based on the Library.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, mere aggregation of another work not based on the Library&#xA;with the Library (or with a work based on the Library) on a volume of&#xA;a storage or distribution medium does not bring the other work under&#xA;the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;3. You may opt to apply the terms of the ordinary GNU General Public&#xA;License instead of this License to a given copy of the Library.  To do&#xA;this, you must alter all the notices that refer to this License, so&#xA;that they refer to the ordinary GNU General Public License, version 2,&#xA;instead of to this License.  (If a newer version than version 2 of the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License has appeared, then you can specify&#xA;that version instead if you wish.)  Do not make any other change in&#xA;these notices.&#xA;&#xA;Once this change is made in a given copy, it is irreversible for&#xA;that copy, so the ordinary GNU General Public License applies to all&#xA;subsequent copies and derivative works made from that copy.&#xA;&#xA;This option is useful when you wish to copy part of the code of&#xA;the Library into a program that is not a library.&#xA;&#xA;4. You may copy and distribute the Library (or a portion or&#xA;derivative of it, under Section 2) in object code or executable form&#xA;under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above provided that you accompany&#xA;it with the complete corresponding machine-readable source code, which&#xA;must be distributed under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above on a&#xA;medium customarily used for software interchange.&#xA;&#xA;If distribution of object code is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, then offering equivalent access to copy the&#xA;source code from the same place satisfies the requirement to&#xA;distribute the source code, even though third parties are not&#xA;compelled to copy the source along with the object code.&#xA;&#xA;5. A program that contains no derivative of any portion of the&#xA;Library, but is designed to work with the Library by being compiled or&#xA;linked with it, is called a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot;.  Such a&#xA;work, in isolation, is not a derivative work of the Library, and&#xA;therefore falls outside the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;However, linking a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library&#xA;creates an executable that is a derivative of the Library (because it&#xA;contains portions of the Library), rather than a &quot;work that uses the&#xA;library&quot;.  The executable is therefore covered by this License.&#xA;Section 6 states terms for distribution of such executables.&#xA;&#xA;When a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; uses material from a header file&#xA;that is part of the Library, the object code for the work may be a&#xA;derivative work of the Library even though the source code is not.&#xA;Whether this is true is especially significant if the work can be&#xA;linked without the Library, or if the work is itself a library.  The&#xA;threshold for this to be true is not precisely defined by law.&#xA;&#xA;If such an object file uses only numerical parameters, data&#xA;structure layouts and accessors, and small macros and small inline&#xA;functions (ten lines or less in length), then the use of the object&#xA;file is unrestricted, regardless of whether it is legally a derivative&#xA;work.  (Executables containing this object code plus portions of the&#xA;Library will still fall under Section 6.)&#xA;&#xA;Otherwise, if the work is a derivative of the Library, you may&#xA;distribute the object code for the work under the terms of Section 6.&#xA;Any executables containing that work also fall under Section 6,&#xA;whether or not they are linked directly with the Library itself.&#xA;&#xA;6. As an exception to the Sections above, you may also combine or&#xA;link a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library to produce a&#xA;work containing portions of the Library, and distribute that work&#xA;under terms of your choice, provided that the terms permit&#xA;modification of the work for the customer&apos;s own use and reverse&#xA;engineering for debugging such modifications.&#xA;&#xA;You must give prominent notice with each copy of the work that the&#xA;Library is used in it and that the Library and its use are covered by&#xA;this License.  You must supply a copy of this License.  If the work&#xA;during execution displays copyright notices, you must include the&#xA;copyright notice for the Library among them, as well as a reference&#xA;directing the user to the copy of this License.  Also, you must do one&#xA;of these things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the work with the complete corresponding&#xA;machine-readable source code for the Library including whatever&#xA;changes were used in the work (which must be distributed under&#xA;Sections 1 and 2 above); and, if the work is an executable linked&#xA;with the Library, with the complete machine-readable &quot;work that&#xA;uses the Library&quot;, as object code and/or source code, so that the&#xA;user can modify the Library and then relink to produce a modified&#xA;executable containing the modified Library.  (It is understood&#xA;that the user who changes the contents of definitions files in the&#xA;Library will not necessarily be able to recompile the application&#xA;to use the modified definitions.)&#xA;&#xA;b) Use a suitable shared library mechanism for linking with the&#xA;Library.  A suitable mechanism is one that (1) uses at run time a&#xA;copy of the library already present on the user&apos;s computer system,&#xA;rather than copying library functions into the executable, and (2)&#xA;will operate properly with a modified version of the library, if&#xA;the user installs one, as long as the modified version is&#xA;interface-compatible with the version that the work was made with.&#xA;&#xA;c) Accompany the work with a written offer, valid for at&#xA;least three years, to give the same user the materials&#xA;specified in Subsection 6a, above, for a charge no more&#xA;than the cost of performing this distribution.&#xA;&#xA;d) If distribution of the work is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, offer equivalent access to copy the above&#xA;specified materials from the same place.&#xA;&#xA;e) Verify that the user has already received a copy of these&#xA;materials or that you have already sent this user a copy.&#xA;&#xA;For an executable, the required form of the &quot;work that uses the&#xA;Library&quot; must include any data and utility programs needed for&#xA;reproducing the executable from it.  However, as a special exception,&#xA;the materials to be distributed need not include anything that is&#xA;normally distributed (in either source or binary form) with the major&#xA;components (compiler, kernel, and so on) of the operating system on&#xA;which the executable runs, unless that component itself accompanies&#xA;the executable.&#xA;&#xA;It may happen that this requirement contradicts the license&#xA;restrictions of other proprietary libraries that do not normally&#xA;accompany the operating system.  Such a contradiction means you cannot&#xA;use both them and the Library together in an executable that you&#xA;distribute.&#xA;&#xA;7. You may place library facilities that are a work based on the&#xA;Library side-by-side in a single library together with other library&#xA;facilities not covered by this License, and distribute such a combined&#xA;library, provided that the separate distribution of the work based on&#xA;the Library and of the other library facilities is otherwise&#xA;permitted, and provided that you do these two things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the combined library with a copy of the same work&#xA;based on the Library, uncombined with any other library&#xA;facilities.  This must be distributed under the terms of the&#xA;Sections above.&#xA;&#xA;b) Give prominent notice with the combined library of the fact&#xA;that part of it is a work based on the Library, and explaining&#xA;where to find the accompanying uncombined form of the same work.&#xA;&#xA;8. You may not copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or distribute&#xA;the Library except as expressly provided under this License.  Any&#xA;attempt otherwise to copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or&#xA;distribute the Library is void, and will automatically terminate your&#xA;rights under this License.  However, parties who have received copies,&#xA;or rights, from you under this License will not have their licenses&#xA;terminated so long as such parties remain in full compliance.&#xA;&#xA;9. You are not required to accept this License, since you have not&#xA;signed it.  However, nothing else grants you permission to modify or&#xA;distribute the Library or its derivative works.  These actions are&#xA;prohibited by law if you do not accept this License.  Therefore, by&#xA;modifying or distributing the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), you indicate your acceptance of this License to do so, and&#xA;all its terms and conditions for copying, distributing or modifying&#xA;the Library or works based on it.&#xA;&#xA;10. Each time you redistribute the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), the recipient automatically receives a license from the&#xA;original licensor to copy, distribute, link with or modify the Library&#xA;subject to these terms and conditions.  You may not impose any further&#xA;restrictions on the recipients&apos; exercise of the rights granted herein.&#xA;You are not responsible for enforcing compliance by third parties with&#xA;this License.&#xA;&#xA;11. If, as a consequence of a court judgment or allegation of patent&#xA;infringement or for any other reason (not limited to patent issues),&#xA;conditions are imposed on you (whether by court order, agreement or&#xA;otherwise) that contradict the conditions of this License, they do not&#xA;excuse you from the conditions of this License.  If you cannot&#xA;distribute so as to satisfy simultaneously your obligations under this&#xA;License and any other pertinent obligations, then as a consequence you&#xA;may not distribute the Library at all.  For example, if a patent&#xA;license would not permit royalty-free redistribution of the Library by&#xA;all those who receive copies directly or indirectly through you, then&#xA;the only way you could satisfy both it and this License would be to&#xA;refrain entirely from distribution of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;If any portion of this section is held invalid or unenforceable under any&#xA;particular circumstance, the balance of the section is intended to apply,&#xA;and the section as a whole is intended to apply in other circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;It is not the purpose of this section to induce you to infringe any&#xA;patents or other property right claims or to contest validity of any&#xA;such claims; this section has the sole purpose of protecting the&#xA;integrity of the free software distribution system which is&#xA;implemented by public license practices.  Many people have made&#xA;generous contributions to the wide range of software distributed&#xA;through that system in reliance on consistent application of that&#xA;system; it is up to the author/donor to decide if he or she is willing&#xA;to distribute software through any other system and a licensee cannot&#xA;impose that choice.&#xA;&#xA;This section is intended to make thoroughly clear what is believed to&#xA;be a consequence of the rest of this License.&#xA;&#xA;12. If the distribution and/or use of the Library is restricted in&#xA;certain countries either by patents or by copyrighted interfaces, the&#xA;original copyright holder who places the Library under this License may add&#xA;an explicit geographical distribution limitation excluding those countries,&#xA;so that distribution is permitted only in or among countries not thus&#xA;excluded.  In such case, this License incorporates the limitation as if&#xA;written in the body of this License.&#xA;&#xA;13. The Free Software Foundation may publish revised and/or new&#xA;versions of the Lesser General Public License from time to time.&#xA;Such new versions will be similar in spirit to the present version,&#xA;but may differ in detail to address new problems or concerns.&#xA;&#xA;Each version is given a distinguishing version number.  If the Library&#xA;specifies a version number of this License which applies to it and&#xA;&quot;any later version&quot;, you have the option of following the terms and&#xA;conditions either of that version or of any later version published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.  If the Library does not specify a&#xA;license version number, you may choose any version ever published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.&#xA;&#xA;14. If you wish to incorporate parts of the Library into other free&#xA;programs whose distribution conditions are incompatible with these,&#xA;write to the author to ask for permission.  For software which is&#xA;copyrighted by the Free Software Foundation, write to the Free&#xA;Software Foundation; we sometimes make exceptions for this.  Our&#xA;decision will be guided by the two goals of preserving the free status&#xA;of all derivatives of our free software and of promoting the sharing&#xA;and reuse of software generally.&#xA;&#xA;NO WARRANTY&#xA;&#xA;15. BECAUSE THE LIBRARY IS LICENSED FREE OF CHARGE, THERE IS NO&#xA;WARRANTY FOR THE LIBRARY, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW.&#xA;EXCEPT WHEN OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND/OR&#xA;OTHER PARTIES PROVIDE THE LIBRARY &quot;AS IS&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY&#xA;KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE&#xA;IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR&#xA;PURPOSE.  THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE&#xA;LIBRARY IS WITH YOU.  SHOULD THE LIBRARY PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME&#xA;THE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.&#xA;&#xA;16. IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN&#xA;WRITING WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MAY MODIFY&#xA;AND/OR REDISTRIBUTE THE LIBRARY AS PERMITTED ABOVE, BE LIABLE TO YOU&#xA;FOR DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR&#xA;CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE&#xA;LIBRARY (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF DATA OR DATA BEING&#xA;RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY YOU OR THIRD PARTIES OR A&#xA;FAILURE OF THE LIBRARY TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER SOFTWARE), EVEN IF&#xA;SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH&#xA;DAMAGES.&#xA;&#xA;END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS&#xA;&#xA;How to Apply These Terms to Your New Libraries&#xA;&#xA;If you develop a new library, and you want it to be of the greatest&#xA;possible use to the public, we recommend making it free software that&#xA;everyone can redistribute and change.  You can do so by permitting&#xA;redistribution under these terms (or, alternatively, under the terms of the&#xA;ordinary General Public License).&#xA;&#xA;To apply these terms, attach the following notices to the library.  It is&#xA;safest to attach them to the start of each source file to most effectively&#xA;convey the exclusion of warranty; and each file should have at least the&#xA;&quot;copyright&quot; line and a pointer to where the full notice is found.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;one line to give the library&apos;s name and a brief idea of what it does.&gt;&#xA;Copyright (C) &lt;year&gt;  &lt;name of author&gt;&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;&#xA;Also add information on how to contact you by electronic and paper mail.&#xA;&#xA;You should also get your employer (if you work as a programmer) or your&#xA;school, if any, to sign a &quot;copyright disclaimer&quot; for the library, if&#xA;necessary.  Here is a sample; alter the names:&#xA;&#xA;Yoyodyne, Inc., hereby disclaims all copyright interest in the&#xA;library `Frob&apos; (a library for tweaking knobs) written by James Random Hacker.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;signature of Ty Coon&gt;, 1 April 1990&#xA;Ty Coon, President of Vice&#xA;&#xA;That&apos;s all there is to it!'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.jar' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='feature' version='1.0.0'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.update.feature' name='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr'/>
      </provides>
      <filter>
        (org.eclipse.update.install.features=true)
      </filter>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='org.eclipse.update.feature' id='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='1'>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
      <licenses size='1'>
        <license uri='%25licenseURL' url='%25licenseURL'>
          %license
        </license>
      </licenses>
      <copyright uri='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html' url='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html'>
        %copyright
      </copyright>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20070717)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86_64&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20070717&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20070717)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.linux.x86&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20070717&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20070717)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' version='2.1.7.3_v20070717'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20070717&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.group' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.group' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='10'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='%featureName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='%description'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description.url' value='http://www.rxtx.org'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.provider' value='%providerName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.type.group' value='true'/>
        <property name='df_LT.featureName' value='RXTX Extender SDK'/>
        <property name='df_LT.providerName' value='RXTX.org'/>
        <property name='df_LT.description' value='RXTX is a library to access serial ports from Java. The SDK Includes End-User Runtime and Source. '/>
        <property name='df_LT.copyright' value='Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.'/>
        <property name='df_LT.license' value='RXTX License v 2.1 - LGPL v 2.1 + Linking Over Controlled Interface.&#xA;RXTX is a native interface to serial ports in java.&#xA;&#xA;Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.&#xA;&#xA;A copy of the LGPL v 2.1 may be found at&#xA;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl.txt on March 4th 2007.  A copy is&#xA;included below for your convenience.&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;An executable that contains no derivative of any portion of RXTX, but&#xA;is designed to work with RXTX by being dynamically linked with it,&#xA;is considered a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; subject to the terms and&#xA;conditions of the GNU Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;The following has been added to the RXTX License to remove&#xA;any confusion about linking to RXTX.   We want to allow in part what&#xA;section 5, paragraph 2 of the LGPL does not permit in the special&#xA;case of linking over a controlled interface.  The intent is to add a&#xA;Java Specification Request or standards body defined interface in the&#xA;future as another exception but one is not currently available.&#xA;&#xA;http://www.fsf.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#LinkingOverControlledInterface&#xA;&#xA;As a special exception, the copyright holders of RXTX give you&#xA;permission to link RXTX with independent modules that communicate with&#xA;RXTX solely through the Sun Microsytems CommAPI interface version 2,&#xA;regardless of the license terms of these independent modules, and to copy&#xA;and distribute the resulting combined work under terms of your choice,&#xA;provided that every copy of the combined work is accompanied by a complete&#xA;copy of the source code of RXTX (the version of RXTX used to produce the&#xA;combined work), being distributed under the terms of the GNU Lesser General&#xA;Public License plus this exception.  An independent module is a&#xA;module which is not derived from or based on RXTX.&#xA;&#xA;Note that people who make modified versions of RXTX are not obligated&#xA;to grant this special exception for their modified versions; it is&#xA;their choice whether to do so.  The GNU Lesser General Public License&#xA;gives permission to release a modified version without this exception; this&#xA;exception also makes it possible to release a modified version which&#xA;carries forward this exception.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA&#xA;All trademarks belong to their respective owners.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;Version 2.1, February 1999&#xA;&#xA;Copyright (C) 1991, 1999 Free Software Foundation, Inc.&#xA;51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies&#xA;of this license document, but changing it is not allowed.&#xA;&#xA;[This is the first released version of the Lesser GPL.  It also counts&#xA;as the successor of the GNU Library Public License, version 2, hence&#xA;the version number 2.1.]&#xA;&#xA;Preamble&#xA;&#xA;The licenses for most software are designed to take away your&#xA;freedom to share and change it.  By contrast, the GNU General Public&#xA;Licenses are intended to guarantee your freedom to share and change&#xA;free software--to make sure the software is free for all its users.&#xA;&#xA;This license, the Lesser General Public License, applies to some&#xA;specially designated software packages--typically libraries--of the&#xA;Free Software Foundation and other authors who decide to use it.  You&#xA;can use it too, but we suggest you first think carefully about whether&#xA;this license or the ordinary General Public License is the better&#xA;strategy to use in any particular case, based on the explanations below.&#xA;&#xA;When we speak of free software, we are referring to freedom of use,&#xA;not price.  Our General Public Licenses are designed to make sure that&#xA;you have the freedom to distribute copies of free software (and charge&#xA;for this service if you wish); that you receive source code or can get&#xA;it if you want it; that you can change the software and use pieces of&#xA;it in new free programs; and that you are informed that you can do&#xA;these things.&#xA;&#xA;To protect your rights, we need to make restrictions that forbid&#xA;distributors to deny you these rights or to ask you to surrender these&#xA;rights.  These restrictions translate to certain responsibilities for&#xA;you if you distribute copies of the library or if you modify it.&#xA;&#xA;For example, if you distribute copies of the library, whether gratis&#xA;or for a fee, you must give the recipients all the rights that we gave&#xA;you.  You must make sure that they, too, receive or can get the source&#xA;code.  If you link other code with the library, you must provide&#xA;complete object files to the recipients, so that they can relink them&#xA;with the library after making changes to the library and recompiling&#xA;it.  And you must show them these terms so they know their rights.&#xA;&#xA;We protect your rights with a two-step method: (1) we copyright the&#xA;library, and (2) we offer you this license, which gives you legal&#xA;permission to copy, distribute and/or modify the library.&#xA;&#xA;To protect each distributor, we want to make it very clear that&#xA;there is no warranty for the free library.  Also, if the library is&#xA;modified by someone else and passed on, the recipients should know&#xA;that what they have is not the original version, so that the original&#xA;author&apos;s reputation will not be affected by problems that might be&#xA;introduced by others.&#xA;&#xA;Finally, software patents pose a constant threat to the existence of&#xA;any free program.  We wish to make sure that a company cannot&#xA;effectively restrict the users of a free program by obtaining a&#xA;restrictive license from a patent holder.  Therefore, we insist that&#xA;any patent license obtained for a version of the library must be&#xA;consistent with the full freedom of use specified in this license.&#xA;&#xA;Most GNU software, including some libraries, is covered by the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License.  This license, the GNU Lesser&#xA;General Public License, applies to certain designated libraries, and&#xA;is quite different from the ordinary General Public License.  We use&#xA;this license for certain libraries in order to permit linking those&#xA;libraries into non-free programs.&#xA;&#xA;When a program is linked with a library, whether statically or using&#xA;a shared library, the combination of the two is legally speaking a&#xA;combined work, a derivative of the original library.  The ordinary&#xA;General Public License therefore permits such linking only if the&#xA;entire combination fits its criteria of freedom.  The Lesser General&#xA;Public License permits more lax criteria for linking other code with&#xA;the library.&#xA;&#xA;We call this license the &quot;Lesser&quot; General Public License because it&#xA;does Less to protect the user&apos;s freedom than the ordinary General&#xA;Public License.  It also provides other free software developers Less&#xA;of an advantage over competing non-free programs.  These disadvantages&#xA;are the reason we use the ordinary General Public License for many&#xA;libraries.  However, the Lesser license provides advantages in certain&#xA;special circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;For example, on rare occasions, there may be a special need to&#xA;encourage the widest possible use of a certain library, so that it becomes&#xA;a de-facto standard.  To achieve this, non-free programs must be&#xA;allowed to use the library.  A more frequent case is that a free&#xA;library does the same job as widely used non-free libraries.  In this&#xA;case, there is little to gain by limiting the free library to free&#xA;software only, so we use the Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;In other cases, permission to use a particular library in non-free&#xA;programs enables a greater number of people to use a large body of&#xA;free software.  For example, permission to use the GNU C Library in&#xA;non-free programs enables many more people to use the whole GNU&#xA;operating system, as well as its variant, the GNU/Linux operating&#xA;system.&#xA;&#xA;Although the Lesser General Public License is Less protective of the&#xA;users&apos; freedom, it does ensure that the user of a program that is&#xA;linked with the Library has the freedom and the wherewithal to run&#xA;that program using a modified version of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;The precise terms and conditions for copying, distribution and&#xA;modification follow.  Pay close attention to the difference between a&#xA;&quot;work based on the library&quot; and a &quot;work that uses the library&quot;.  The&#xA;former contains code derived from the library, whereas the latter must&#xA;be combined with the library in order to run.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR COPYING, DISTRIBUTION AND MODIFICATION&#xA;&#xA;0. This License Agreement applies to any software library or other&#xA;program which contains a notice placed by the copyright holder or&#xA;other authorized party saying it may be distributed under the terms of&#xA;this Lesser General Public License (also called &quot;this License&quot;).&#xA;Each licensee is addressed as &quot;you&quot;.&#xA;&#xA;A &quot;library&quot; means a collection of software functions and/or data&#xA;prepared so as to be conveniently linked with application programs&#xA;(which use some of those functions and data) to form executables.&#xA;&#xA;The &quot;Library&quot;, below, refers to any such software library or work&#xA;which has been distributed under these terms.  A &quot;work based on the&#xA;Library&quot; means either the Library or any derivative work under&#xA;copyright law: that is to say, a work containing the Library or a&#xA;portion of it, either verbatim or with modifications and/or translated&#xA;straightforwardly into another language.  (Hereinafter, translation is&#xA;included without limitation in the term &quot;modification&quot;.)&#xA;&#xA;&quot;Source code&quot; for a work means the preferred form of the work for&#xA;making modifications to it.  For a library, complete source code means&#xA;all the source code for all modules it contains, plus any associated&#xA;interface definition files, plus the scripts used to control compilation&#xA;and installation of the library.&#xA;&#xA;Activities other than copying, distribution and modification are not&#xA;covered by this License; they are outside its scope.  The act of&#xA;running a program using the Library is not restricted, and output from&#xA;such a program is covered only if its contents constitute a work based&#xA;on the Library (independent of the use of the Library in a tool for&#xA;writing it).  Whether that is true depends on what the Library does&#xA;and what the program that uses the Library does.&#xA;&#xA;1. You may copy and distribute verbatim copies of the Library&apos;s&#xA;complete source code as you receive it, in any medium, provided that&#xA;you conspicuously and appropriately publish on each copy an&#xA;appropriate copyright notice and disclaimer of warranty; keep intact&#xA;all the notices that refer to this License and to the absence of any&#xA;warranty; and distribute a copy of this License along with the&#xA;Library.&#xA;&#xA;You may charge a fee for the physical act of transferring a copy,&#xA;and you may at your option offer warranty protection in exchange for a&#xA;fee.&#xA;&#xA;2. You may modify your copy or copies of the Library or any portion&#xA;of it, thus forming a work based on the Library, and copy and&#xA;distribute such modifications or work under the terms of Section 1&#xA;above, provided that you also meet all of these conditions:&#xA;&#xA;a) The modified work must itself be a software library.&#xA;&#xA;b) You must cause the files modified to carry prominent notices&#xA;stating that you changed the files and the date of any change.&#xA;&#xA;c) You must cause the whole of the work to be licensed at no&#xA;charge to all third parties under the terms of this License.&#xA;&#xA;d) If a facility in the modified Library refers to a function or a&#xA;table of data to be supplied by an application program that uses&#xA;the facility, other than as an argument passed when the facility&#xA;is invoked, then you must make a good faith effort to ensure that,&#xA;in the event an application does not supply such function or&#xA;table, the facility still operates, and performs whatever part of&#xA;its purpose remains meaningful.&#xA;&#xA;(For example, a function in a library to compute square roots has&#xA;a purpose that is entirely well-defined independent of the&#xA;application.  Therefore, Subsection 2d requires that any&#xA;application-supplied function or table used by this function must&#xA;be optional: if the application does not supply it, the square&#xA;root function must still compute square roots.)&#xA;&#xA;These requirements apply to the modified work as a whole.  If&#xA;identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Library,&#xA;and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in&#xA;themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those&#xA;sections when you distribute them as separate works.  But when you&#xA;distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based&#xA;on the Library, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of&#xA;this License, whose permissions for other licensees extend to the&#xA;entire whole, and thus to each and every part regardless of who wrote&#xA;it.&#xA;&#xA;Thus, it is not the intent of this section to claim rights or contest&#xA;your rights to work written entirely by you; rather, the intent is to&#xA;exercise the right to control the distribution of derivative or&#xA;collective works based on the Library.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, mere aggregation of another work not based on the Library&#xA;with the Library (or with a work based on the Library) on a volume of&#xA;a storage or distribution medium does not bring the other work under&#xA;the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;3. You may opt to apply the terms of the ordinary GNU General Public&#xA;License instead of this License to a given copy of the Library.  To do&#xA;this, you must alter all the notices that refer to this License, so&#xA;that they refer to the ordinary GNU General Public License, version 2,&#xA;instead of to this License.  (If a newer version than version 2 of the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License has appeared, then you can specify&#xA;that version instead if you wish.)  Do not make any other change in&#xA;these notices.&#xA;&#xA;Once this change is made in a given copy, it is irreversible for&#xA;that copy, so the ordinary GNU General Public License applies to all&#xA;subsequent copies and derivative works made from that copy.&#xA;&#xA;This option is useful when you wish to copy part of the code of&#xA;the Library into a program that is not a library.&#xA;&#xA;4. You may copy and distribute the Library (or a portion or&#xA;derivative of it, under Section 2) in object code or executable form&#xA;under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above provided that you accompany&#xA;it with the complete corresponding machine-readable source code, which&#xA;must be distributed under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above on a&#xA;medium customarily used for software interchange.&#xA;&#xA;If distribution of object code is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, then offering equivalent access to copy the&#xA;source code from the same place satisfies the requirement to&#xA;distribute the source code, even though third parties are not&#xA;compelled to copy the source along with the object code.&#xA;&#xA;5. A program that contains no derivative of any portion of the&#xA;Library, but is designed to work with the Library by being compiled or&#xA;linked with it, is called a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot;.  Such a&#xA;work, in isolation, is not a derivative work of the Library, and&#xA;therefore falls outside the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;However, linking a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library&#xA;creates an executable that is a derivative of the Library (because it&#xA;contains portions of the Library), rather than a &quot;work that uses the&#xA;library&quot;.  The executable is therefore covered by this License.&#xA;Section 6 states terms for distribution of such executables.&#xA;&#xA;When a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; uses material from a header file&#xA;that is part of the Library, the object code for the work may be a&#xA;derivative work of the Library even though the source code is not.&#xA;Whether this is true is especially significant if the work can be&#xA;linked without the Library, or if the work is itself a library.  The&#xA;threshold for this to be true is not precisely defined by law.&#xA;&#xA;If such an object file uses only numerical parameters, data&#xA;structure layouts and accessors, and small macros and small inline&#xA;functions (ten lines or less in length), then the use of the object&#xA;file is unrestricted, regardless of whether it is legally a derivative&#xA;work.  (Executables containing this object code plus portions of the&#xA;Library will still fall under Section 6.)&#xA;&#xA;Otherwise, if the work is a derivative of the Library, you may&#xA;distribute the object code for the work under the terms of Section 6.&#xA;Any executables containing that work also fall under Section 6,&#xA;whether or not they are linked directly with the Library itself.&#xA;&#xA;6. As an exception to the Sections above, you may also combine or&#xA;link a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library to produce a&#xA;work containing portions of the Library, and distribute that work&#xA;under terms of your choice, provided that the terms permit&#xA;modification of the work for the customer&apos;s own use and reverse&#xA;engineering for debugging such modifications.&#xA;&#xA;You must give prominent notice with each copy of the work that the&#xA;Library is used in it and that the Library and its use are covered by&#xA;this License.  You must supply a copy of this License.  If the work&#xA;during execution displays copyright notices, you must include the&#xA;copyright notice for the Library among them, as well as a reference&#xA;directing the user to the copy of this License.  Also, you must do one&#xA;of these things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the work with the complete corresponding&#xA;machine-readable source code for the Library including whatever&#xA;changes were used in the work (which must be distributed under&#xA;Sections 1 and 2 above); and, if the work is an executable linked&#xA;with the Library, with the complete machine-readable &quot;work that&#xA;uses the Library&quot;, as object code and/or source code, so that the&#xA;user can modify the Library and then relink to produce a modified&#xA;executable containing the modified Library.  (It is understood&#xA;that the user who changes the contents of definitions files in the&#xA;Library will not necessarily be able to recompile the application&#xA;to use the modified definitions.)&#xA;&#xA;b) Use a suitable shared library mechanism for linking with the&#xA;Library.  A suitable mechanism is one that (1) uses at run time a&#xA;copy of the library already present on the user&apos;s computer system,&#xA;rather than copying library functions into the executable, and (2)&#xA;will operate properly with a modified version of the library, if&#xA;the user installs one, as long as the modified version is&#xA;interface-compatible with the version that the work was made with.&#xA;&#xA;c) Accompany the work with a written offer, valid for at&#xA;least three years, to give the same user the materials&#xA;specified in Subsection 6a, above, for a charge no more&#xA;than the cost of performing this distribution.&#xA;&#xA;d) If distribution of the work is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, offer equivalent access to copy the above&#xA;specified materials from the same place.&#xA;&#xA;e) Verify that the user has already received a copy of these&#xA;materials or that you have already sent this user a copy.&#xA;&#xA;For an executable, the required form of the &quot;work that uses the&#xA;Library&quot; must include any data and utility programs needed for&#xA;reproducing the executable from it.  However, as a special exception,&#xA;the materials to be distributed need not include anything that is&#xA;normally distributed (in either source or binary form) with the major&#xA;components (compiler, kernel, and so on) of the operating system on&#xA;which the executable runs, unless that component itself accompanies&#xA;the executable.&#xA;&#xA;It may happen that this requirement contradicts the license&#xA;restrictions of other proprietary libraries that do not normally&#xA;accompany the operating system.  Such a contradiction means you cannot&#xA;use both them and the Library together in an executable that you&#xA;distribute.&#xA;&#xA;7. You may place library facilities that are a work based on the&#xA;Library side-by-side in a single library together with other library&#xA;facilities not covered by this License, and distribute such a combined&#xA;library, provided that the separate distribution of the work based on&#xA;the Library and of the other library facilities is otherwise&#xA;permitted, and provided that you do these two things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the combined library with a copy of the same work&#xA;based on the Library, uncombined with any other library&#xA;facilities.  This must be distributed under the terms of the&#xA;Sections above.&#xA;&#xA;b) Give prominent notice with the combined library of the fact&#xA;that part of it is a work based on the Library, and explaining&#xA;where to find the accompanying uncombined form of the same work.&#xA;&#xA;8. You may not copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or distribute&#xA;the Library except as expressly provided under this License.  Any&#xA;attempt otherwise to copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or&#xA;distribute the Library is void, and will automatically terminate your&#xA;rights under this License.  However, parties who have received copies,&#xA;or rights, from you under this License will not have their licenses&#xA;terminated so long as such parties remain in full compliance.&#xA;&#xA;9. You are not required to accept this License, since you have not&#xA;signed it.  However, nothing else grants you permission to modify or&#xA;distribute the Library or its derivative works.  These actions are&#xA;prohibited by law if you do not accept this License.  Therefore, by&#xA;modifying or distributing the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), you indicate your acceptance of this License to do so, and&#xA;all its terms and conditions for copying, distributing or modifying&#xA;the Library or works based on it.&#xA;&#xA;10. Each time you redistribute the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), the recipient automatically receives a license from the&#xA;original licensor to copy, distribute, link with or modify the Library&#xA;subject to these terms and conditions.  You may not impose any further&#xA;restrictions on the recipients&apos; exercise of the rights granted herein.&#xA;You are not responsible for enforcing compliance by third parties with&#xA;this License.&#xA;&#xA;11. If, as a consequence of a court judgment or allegation of patent&#xA;infringement or for any other reason (not limited to patent issues),&#xA;conditions are imposed on you (whether by court order, agreement or&#xA;otherwise) that contradict the conditions of this License, they do not&#xA;excuse you from the conditions of this License.  If you cannot&#xA;distribute so as to satisfy simultaneously your obligations under this&#xA;License and any other pertinent obligations, then as a consequence you&#xA;may not distribute the Library at all.  For example, if a patent&#xA;license would not permit royalty-free redistribution of the Library by&#xA;all those who receive copies directly or indirectly through you, then&#xA;the only way you could satisfy both it and this License would be to&#xA;refrain entirely from distribution of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;If any portion of this section is held invalid or unenforceable under any&#xA;particular circumstance, the balance of the section is intended to apply,&#xA;and the section as a whole is intended to apply in other circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;It is not the purpose of this section to induce you to infringe any&#xA;patents or other property right claims or to contest validity of any&#xA;such claims; this section has the sole purpose of protecting the&#xA;integrity of the free software distribution system which is&#xA;implemented by public license practices.  Many people have made&#xA;generous contributions to the wide range of software distributed&#xA;through that system in reliance on consistent application of that&#xA;system; it is up to the author/donor to decide if he or she is willing&#xA;to distribute software through any other system and a licensee cannot&#xA;impose that choice.&#xA;&#xA;This section is intended to make thoroughly clear what is believed to&#xA;be a consequence of the rest of this License.&#xA;&#xA;12. If the distribution and/or use of the Library is restricted in&#xA;certain countries either by patents or by copyrighted interfaces, the&#xA;original copyright holder who places the Library under this License may add&#xA;an explicit geographical distribution limitation excluding those countries,&#xA;so that distribution is permitted only in or among countries not thus&#xA;excluded.  In such case, this License incorporates the limitation as if&#xA;written in the body of this License.&#xA;&#xA;13. The Free Software Foundation may publish revised and/or new&#xA;versions of the Lesser General Public License from time to time.&#xA;Such new versions will be similar in spirit to the present version,&#xA;but may differ in detail to address new problems or concerns.&#xA;&#xA;Each version is given a distinguishing version number.  If the Library&#xA;specifies a version number of this License which applies to it and&#xA;&quot;any later version&quot;, you have the option of following the terms and&#xA;conditions either of that version or of any later version published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.  If the Library does not specify a&#xA;license version number, you may choose any version ever published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.&#xA;&#xA;14. If you wish to incorporate parts of the Library into other free&#xA;programs whose distribution conditions are incompatible with these,&#xA;write to the author to ask for permission.  For software which is&#xA;copyrighted by the Free Software Foundation, write to the Free&#xA;Software Foundation; we sometimes make exceptions for this.  Our&#xA;decision will be guided by the two goals of preserving the free status&#xA;of all derivatives of our free software and of promoting the sharing&#xA;and reuse of software generally.&#xA;&#xA;NO WARRANTY&#xA;&#xA;15. BECAUSE THE LIBRARY IS LICENSED FREE OF CHARGE, THERE IS NO&#xA;WARRANTY FOR THE LIBRARY, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW.&#xA;EXCEPT WHEN OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND/OR&#xA;OTHER PARTIES PROVIDE THE LIBRARY &quot;AS IS&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY&#xA;KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE&#xA;IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR&#xA;PURPOSE.  THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE&#xA;LIBRARY IS WITH YOU.  SHOULD THE LIBRARY PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME&#xA;THE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.&#xA;&#xA;16. IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN&#xA;WRITING WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MAY MODIFY&#xA;AND/OR REDISTRIBUTE THE LIBRARY AS PERMITTED ABOVE, BE LIABLE TO YOU&#xA;FOR DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR&#xA;CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE&#xA;LIBRARY (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF DATA OR DATA BEING&#xA;RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY YOU OR THIRD PARTIES OR A&#xA;FAILURE OF THE LIBRARY TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER SOFTWARE), EVEN IF&#xA;SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH&#xA;DAMAGES.&#xA;&#xA;END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS&#xA;&#xA;How to Apply These Terms to Your New Libraries&#xA;&#xA;If you develop a new library, and you want it to be of the greatest&#xA;possible use to the public, we recommend making it free software that&#xA;everyone can redistribute and change.  You can do so by permitting&#xA;redistribution under these terms (or, alternatively, under the terms of the&#xA;ordinary General Public License).&#xA;&#xA;To apply these terms, attach the following notices to the library.  It is&#xA;safest to attach them to the start of each source file to most effectively&#xA;convey the exclusion of warranty; and each file should have at least the&#xA;&quot;copyright&quot; line and a pointer to where the full notice is found.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;one line to give the library&apos;s name and a brief idea of what it does.&gt;&#xA;Copyright (C) &lt;year&gt;  &lt;name of author&gt;&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;&#xA;Also add information on how to contact you by electronic and paper mail.&#xA;&#xA;You should also get your employer (if you work as a programmer) or your&#xA;school, if any, to sign a &quot;copyright disclaimer&quot; for the library, if&#xA;necessary.  Here is a sample; alter the names:&#xA;&#xA;Yoyodyne, Inc., hereby disclaims all copyright interest in the&#xA;library `Frob&apos; (a library for tweaking knobs) written by James Random Hacker.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;signature of Ty Coon&gt;, 1 April 1990&#xA;Ty Coon, President of Vice&#xA;&#xA;That&apos;s all there is to it!'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='2'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.group' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.localization' name='df_LT' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <requires size='3'>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.group' range='[2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf,2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf]'/>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.source' range='[2.1.7.4_v20071016,2.1.7.4_v20071016]'/>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.jar' range='[2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg,2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg]'>
          <filter>
            (org.eclipse.update.install.features=true)
          </filter>
        </required>
      </requires>
      <touchpoint id='null' version='0.0.0'/>
      <licenses size='1'>
        <license uri='%25licenseURL' url='%25licenseURL'>
          %license
        </license>
      </licenses>
      <copyright uri='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html' url='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html'>
        %copyright
      </copyright>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.group' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.group' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='10'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='%featureName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='%description'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description.url' value='http://www.rxtx.org'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.provider' value='%providerName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.type.group' value='true'/>
        <property name='df_LT.featureName' value='RXTX Extender SDK'/>
        <property name='df_LT.providerName' value='RXTX.org'/>
        <property name='df_LT.description' value='RXTX is a library to access serial ports from Java. The SDK Includes End-User Runtime and Source. '/>
        <property name='df_LT.copyright' value='Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.'/>
        <property name='df_LT.license' value='RXTX License v 2.1 - LGPL v 2.1 + Linking Over Controlled Interface.&#xA;RXTX is a native interface to serial ports in java.&#xA;&#xA;Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.&#xA;&#xA;A copy of the LGPL v 2.1 may be found at&#xA;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl.txt on March 4th 2007.  A copy is&#xA;included below for your convenience.&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;An executable that contains no derivative of any portion of RXTX, but&#xA;is designed to work with RXTX by being dynamically linked with it,&#xA;is considered a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; subject to the terms and&#xA;conditions of the GNU Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;The following has been added to the RXTX License to remove&#xA;any confusion about linking to RXTX.   We want to allow in part what&#xA;section 5, paragraph 2 of the LGPL does not permit in the special&#xA;case of linking over a controlled interface.  The intent is to add a&#xA;Java Specification Request or standards body defined interface in the&#xA;future as another exception but one is not currently available.&#xA;&#xA;http://www.fsf.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#LinkingOverControlledInterface&#xA;&#xA;As a special exception, the copyright holders of RXTX give you&#xA;permission to link RXTX with independent modules that communicate with&#xA;RXTX solely through the Sun Microsytems CommAPI interface version 2,&#xA;regardless of the license terms of these independent modules, and to copy&#xA;and distribute the resulting combined work under terms of your choice,&#xA;provided that every copy of the combined work is accompanied by a complete&#xA;copy of the source code of RXTX (the version of RXTX used to produce the&#xA;combined work), being distributed under the terms of the GNU Lesser General&#xA;Public License plus this exception.  An independent module is a&#xA;module which is not derived from or based on RXTX.&#xA;&#xA;Note that people who make modified versions of RXTX are not obligated&#xA;to grant this special exception for their modified versions; it is&#xA;their choice whether to do so.  The GNU Lesser General Public License&#xA;gives permission to release a modified version without this exception; this&#xA;exception also makes it possible to release a modified version which&#xA;carries forward this exception.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA&#xA;All trademarks belong to their respective owners.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;Version 2.1, February 1999&#xA;&#xA;Copyright (C) 1991, 1999 Free Software Foundation, Inc.&#xA;51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies&#xA;of this license document, but changing it is not allowed.&#xA;&#xA;[This is the first released version of the Lesser GPL.  It also counts&#xA;as the successor of the GNU Library Public License, version 2, hence&#xA;the version number 2.1.]&#xA;&#xA;Preamble&#xA;&#xA;The licenses for most software are designed to take away your&#xA;freedom to share and change it.  By contrast, the GNU General Public&#xA;Licenses are intended to guarantee your freedom to share and change&#xA;free software--to make sure the software is free for all its users.&#xA;&#xA;This license, the Lesser General Public License, applies to some&#xA;specially designated software packages--typically libraries--of the&#xA;Free Software Foundation and other authors who decide to use it.  You&#xA;can use it too, but we suggest you first think carefully about whether&#xA;this license or the ordinary General Public License is the better&#xA;strategy to use in any particular case, based on the explanations below.&#xA;&#xA;When we speak of free software, we are referring to freedom of use,&#xA;not price.  Our General Public Licenses are designed to make sure that&#xA;you have the freedom to distribute copies of free software (and charge&#xA;for this service if you wish); that you receive source code or can get&#xA;it if you want it; that you can change the software and use pieces of&#xA;it in new free programs; and that you are informed that you can do&#xA;these things.&#xA;&#xA;To protect your rights, we need to make restrictions that forbid&#xA;distributors to deny you these rights or to ask you to surrender these&#xA;rights.  These restrictions translate to certain responsibilities for&#xA;you if you distribute copies of the library or if you modify it.&#xA;&#xA;For example, if you distribute copies of the library, whether gratis&#xA;or for a fee, you must give the recipients all the rights that we gave&#xA;you.  You must make sure that they, too, receive or can get the source&#xA;code.  If you link other code with the library, you must provide&#xA;complete object files to the recipients, so that they can relink them&#xA;with the library after making changes to the library and recompiling&#xA;it.  And you must show them these terms so they know their rights.&#xA;&#xA;We protect your rights with a two-step method: (1) we copyright the&#xA;library, and (2) we offer you this license, which gives you legal&#xA;permission to copy, distribute and/or modify the library.&#xA;&#xA;To protect each distributor, we want to make it very clear that&#xA;there is no warranty for the free library.  Also, if the library is&#xA;modified by someone else and passed on, the recipients should know&#xA;that what they have is not the original version, so that the original&#xA;author&apos;s reputation will not be affected by problems that might be&#xA;introduced by others.&#xA;&#xA;Finally, software patents pose a constant threat to the existence of&#xA;any free program.  We wish to make sure that a company cannot&#xA;effectively restrict the users of a free program by obtaining a&#xA;restrictive license from a patent holder.  Therefore, we insist that&#xA;any patent license obtained for a version of the library must be&#xA;consistent with the full freedom of use specified in this license.&#xA;&#xA;Most GNU software, including some libraries, is covered by the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License.  This license, the GNU Lesser&#xA;General Public License, applies to certain designated libraries, and&#xA;is quite different from the ordinary General Public License.  We use&#xA;this license for certain libraries in order to permit linking those&#xA;libraries into non-free programs.&#xA;&#xA;When a program is linked with a library, whether statically or using&#xA;a shared library, the combination of the two is legally speaking a&#xA;combined work, a derivative of the original library.  The ordinary&#xA;General Public License therefore permits such linking only if the&#xA;entire combination fits its criteria of freedom.  The Lesser General&#xA;Public License permits more lax criteria for linking other code with&#xA;the library.&#xA;&#xA;We call this license the &quot;Lesser&quot; General Public License because it&#xA;does Less to protect the user&apos;s freedom than the ordinary General&#xA;Public License.  It also provides other free software developers Less&#xA;of an advantage over competing non-free programs.  These disadvantages&#xA;are the reason we use the ordinary General Public License for many&#xA;libraries.  However, the Lesser license provides advantages in certain&#xA;special circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;For example, on rare occasions, there may be a special need to&#xA;encourage the widest possible use of a certain library, so that it becomes&#xA;a de-facto standard.  To achieve this, non-free programs must be&#xA;allowed to use the library.  A more frequent case is that a free&#xA;library does the same job as widely used non-free libraries.  In this&#xA;case, there is little to gain by limiting the free library to free&#xA;software only, so we use the Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;In other cases, permission to use a particular library in non-free&#xA;programs enables a greater number of people to use a large body of&#xA;free software.  For example, permission to use the GNU C Library in&#xA;non-free programs enables many more people to use the whole GNU&#xA;operating system, as well as its variant, the GNU/Linux operating&#xA;system.&#xA;&#xA;Although the Lesser General Public License is Less protective of the&#xA;users&apos; freedom, it does ensure that the user of a program that is&#xA;linked with the Library has the freedom and the wherewithal to run&#xA;that program using a modified version of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;The precise terms and conditions for copying, distribution and&#xA;modification follow.  Pay close attention to the difference between a&#xA;&quot;work based on the library&quot; and a &quot;work that uses the library&quot;.  The&#xA;former contains code derived from the library, whereas the latter must&#xA;be combined with the library in order to run.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR COPYING, DISTRIBUTION AND MODIFICATION&#xA;&#xA;0. This License Agreement applies to any software library or other&#xA;program which contains a notice placed by the copyright holder or&#xA;other authorized party saying it may be distributed under the terms of&#xA;this Lesser General Public License (also called &quot;this License&quot;).&#xA;Each licensee is addressed as &quot;you&quot;.&#xA;&#xA;A &quot;library&quot; means a collection of software functions and/or data&#xA;prepared so as to be conveniently linked with application programs&#xA;(which use some of those functions and data) to form executables.&#xA;&#xA;The &quot;Library&quot;, below, refers to any such software library or work&#xA;which has been distributed under these terms.  A &quot;work based on the&#xA;Library&quot; means either the Library or any derivative work under&#xA;copyright law: that is to say, a work containing the Library or a&#xA;portion of it, either verbatim or with modifications and/or translated&#xA;straightforwardly into another language.  (Hereinafter, translation is&#xA;included without limitation in the term &quot;modification&quot;.)&#xA;&#xA;&quot;Source code&quot; for a work means the preferred form of the work for&#xA;making modifications to it.  For a library, complete source code means&#xA;all the source code for all modules it contains, plus any associated&#xA;interface definition files, plus the scripts used to control compilation&#xA;and installation of the library.&#xA;&#xA;Activities other than copying, distribution and modification are not&#xA;covered by this License; they are outside its scope.  The act of&#xA;running a program using the Library is not restricted, and output from&#xA;such a program is covered only if its contents constitute a work based&#xA;on the Library (independent of the use of the Library in a tool for&#xA;writing it).  Whether that is true depends on what the Library does&#xA;and what the program that uses the Library does.&#xA;&#xA;1. You may copy and distribute verbatim copies of the Library&apos;s&#xA;complete source code as you receive it, in any medium, provided that&#xA;you conspicuously and appropriately publish on each copy an&#xA;appropriate copyright notice and disclaimer of warranty; keep intact&#xA;all the notices that refer to this License and to the absence of any&#xA;warranty; and distribute a copy of this License along with the&#xA;Library.&#xA;&#xA;You may charge a fee for the physical act of transferring a copy,&#xA;and you may at your option offer warranty protection in exchange for a&#xA;fee.&#xA;&#xA;2. You may modify your copy or copies of the Library or any portion&#xA;of it, thus forming a work based on the Library, and copy and&#xA;distribute such modifications or work under the terms of Section 1&#xA;above, provided that you also meet all of these conditions:&#xA;&#xA;a) The modified work must itself be a software library.&#xA;&#xA;b) You must cause the files modified to carry prominent notices&#xA;stating that you changed the files and the date of any change.&#xA;&#xA;c) You must cause the whole of the work to be licensed at no&#xA;charge to all third parties under the terms of this License.&#xA;&#xA;d) If a facility in the modified Library refers to a function or a&#xA;table of data to be supplied by an application program that uses&#xA;the facility, other than as an argument passed when the facility&#xA;is invoked, then you must make a good faith effort to ensure that,&#xA;in the event an application does not supply such function or&#xA;table, the facility still operates, and performs whatever part of&#xA;its purpose remains meaningful.&#xA;&#xA;(For example, a function in a library to compute square roots has&#xA;a purpose that is entirely well-defined independent of the&#xA;application.  Therefore, Subsection 2d requires that any&#xA;application-supplied function or table used by this function must&#xA;be optional: if the application does not supply it, the square&#xA;root function must still compute square roots.)&#xA;&#xA;These requirements apply to the modified work as a whole.  If&#xA;identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Library,&#xA;and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in&#xA;themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those&#xA;sections when you distribute them as separate works.  But when you&#xA;distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based&#xA;on the Library, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of&#xA;this License, whose permissions for other licensees extend to the&#xA;entire whole, and thus to each and every part regardless of who wrote&#xA;it.&#xA;&#xA;Thus, it is not the intent of this section to claim rights or contest&#xA;your rights to work written entirely by you; rather, the intent is to&#xA;exercise the right to control the distribution of derivative or&#xA;collective works based on the Library.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, mere aggregation of another work not based on the Library&#xA;with the Library (or with a work based on the Library) on a volume of&#xA;a storage or distribution medium does not bring the other work under&#xA;the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;3. You may opt to apply the terms of the ordinary GNU General Public&#xA;License instead of this License to a given copy of the Library.  To do&#xA;this, you must alter all the notices that refer to this License, so&#xA;that they refer to the ordinary GNU General Public License, version 2,&#xA;instead of to this License.  (If a newer version than version 2 of the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License has appeared, then you can specify&#xA;that version instead if you wish.)  Do not make any other change in&#xA;these notices.&#xA;&#xA;Once this change is made in a given copy, it is irreversible for&#xA;that copy, so the ordinary GNU General Public License applies to all&#xA;subsequent copies and derivative works made from that copy.&#xA;&#xA;This option is useful when you wish to copy part of the code of&#xA;the Library into a program that is not a library.&#xA;&#xA;4. You may copy and distribute the Library (or a portion or&#xA;derivative of it, under Section 2) in object code or executable form&#xA;under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above provided that you accompany&#xA;it with the complete corresponding machine-readable source code, which&#xA;must be distributed under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above on a&#xA;medium customarily used for software interchange.&#xA;&#xA;If distribution of object code is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, then offering equivalent access to copy the&#xA;source code from the same place satisfies the requirement to&#xA;distribute the source code, even though third parties are not&#xA;compelled to copy the source along with the object code.&#xA;&#xA;5. A program that contains no derivative of any portion of the&#xA;Library, but is designed to work with the Library by being compiled or&#xA;linked with it, is called a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot;.  Such a&#xA;work, in isolation, is not a derivative work of the Library, and&#xA;therefore falls outside the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;However, linking a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library&#xA;creates an executable that is a derivative of the Library (because it&#xA;contains portions of the Library), rather than a &quot;work that uses the&#xA;library&quot;.  The executable is therefore covered by this License.&#xA;Section 6 states terms for distribution of such executables.&#xA;&#xA;When a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; uses material from a header file&#xA;that is part of the Library, the object code for the work may be a&#xA;derivative work of the Library even though the source code is not.&#xA;Whether this is true is especially significant if the work can be&#xA;linked without the Library, or if the work is itself a library.  The&#xA;threshold for this to be true is not precisely defined by law.&#xA;&#xA;If such an object file uses only numerical parameters, data&#xA;structure layouts and accessors, and small macros and small inline&#xA;functions (ten lines or less in length), then the use of the object&#xA;file is unrestricted, regardless of whether it is legally a derivative&#xA;work.  (Executables containing this object code plus portions of the&#xA;Library will still fall under Section 6.)&#xA;&#xA;Otherwise, if the work is a derivative of the Library, you may&#xA;distribute the object code for the work under the terms of Section 6.&#xA;Any executables containing that work also fall under Section 6,&#xA;whether or not they are linked directly with the Library itself.&#xA;&#xA;6. As an exception to the Sections above, you may also combine or&#xA;link a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library to produce a&#xA;work containing portions of the Library, and distribute that work&#xA;under terms of your choice, provided that the terms permit&#xA;modification of the work for the customer&apos;s own use and reverse&#xA;engineering for debugging such modifications.&#xA;&#xA;You must give prominent notice with each copy of the work that the&#xA;Library is used in it and that the Library and its use are covered by&#xA;this License.  You must supply a copy of this License.  If the work&#xA;during execution displays copyright notices, you must include the&#xA;copyright notice for the Library among them, as well as a reference&#xA;directing the user to the copy of this License.  Also, you must do one&#xA;of these things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the work with the complete corresponding&#xA;machine-readable source code for the Library including whatever&#xA;changes were used in the work (which must be distributed under&#xA;Sections 1 and 2 above); and, if the work is an executable linked&#xA;with the Library, with the complete machine-readable &quot;work that&#xA;uses the Library&quot;, as object code and/or source code, so that the&#xA;user can modify the Library and then relink to produce a modified&#xA;executable containing the modified Library.  (It is understood&#xA;that the user who changes the contents of definitions files in the&#xA;Library will not necessarily be able to recompile the application&#xA;to use the modified definitions.)&#xA;&#xA;b) Use a suitable shared library mechanism for linking with the&#xA;Library.  A suitable mechanism is one that (1) uses at run time a&#xA;copy of the library already present on the user&apos;s computer system,&#xA;rather than copying library functions into the executable, and (2)&#xA;will operate properly with a modified version of the library, if&#xA;the user installs one, as long as the modified version is&#xA;interface-compatible with the version that the work was made with.&#xA;&#xA;c) Accompany the work with a written offer, valid for at&#xA;least three years, to give the same user the materials&#xA;specified in Subsection 6a, above, for a charge no more&#xA;than the cost of performing this distribution.&#xA;&#xA;d) If distribution of the work is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, offer equivalent access to copy the above&#xA;specified materials from the same place.&#xA;&#xA;e) Verify that the user has already received a copy of these&#xA;materials or that you have already sent this user a copy.&#xA;&#xA;For an executable, the required form of the &quot;work that uses the&#xA;Library&quot; must include any data and utility programs needed for&#xA;reproducing the executable from it.  However, as a special exception,&#xA;the materials to be distributed need not include anything that is&#xA;normally distributed (in either source or binary form) with the major&#xA;components (compiler, kernel, and so on) of the operating system on&#xA;which the executable runs, unless that component itself accompanies&#xA;the executable.&#xA;&#xA;It may happen that this requirement contradicts the license&#xA;restrictions of other proprietary libraries that do not normally&#xA;accompany the operating system.  Such a contradiction means you cannot&#xA;use both them and the Library together in an executable that you&#xA;distribute.&#xA;&#xA;7. You may place library facilities that are a work based on the&#xA;Library side-by-side in a single library together with other library&#xA;facilities not covered by this License, and distribute such a combined&#xA;library, provided that the separate distribution of the work based on&#xA;the Library and of the other library facilities is otherwise&#xA;permitted, and provided that you do these two things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the combined library with a copy of the same work&#xA;based on the Library, uncombined with any other library&#xA;facilities.  This must be distributed under the terms of the&#xA;Sections above.&#xA;&#xA;b) Give prominent notice with the combined library of the fact&#xA;that part of it is a work based on the Library, and explaining&#xA;where to find the accompanying uncombined form of the same work.&#xA;&#xA;8. You may not copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or distribute&#xA;the Library except as expressly provided under this License.  Any&#xA;attempt otherwise to copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or&#xA;distribute the Library is void, and will automatically terminate your&#xA;rights under this License.  However, parties who have received copies,&#xA;or rights, from you under this License will not have their licenses&#xA;terminated so long as such parties remain in full compliance.&#xA;&#xA;9. You are not required to accept this License, since you have not&#xA;signed it.  However, nothing else grants you permission to modify or&#xA;distribute the Library or its derivative works.  These actions are&#xA;prohibited by law if you do not accept this License.  Therefore, by&#xA;modifying or distributing the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), you indicate your acceptance of this License to do so, and&#xA;all its terms and conditions for copying, distributing or modifying&#xA;the Library or works based on it.&#xA;&#xA;10. Each time you redistribute the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), the recipient automatically receives a license from the&#xA;original licensor to copy, distribute, link with or modify the Library&#xA;subject to these terms and conditions.  You may not impose any further&#xA;restrictions on the recipients&apos; exercise of the rights granted herein.&#xA;You are not responsible for enforcing compliance by third parties with&#xA;this License.&#xA;&#xA;11. If, as a consequence of a court judgment or allegation of patent&#xA;infringement or for any other reason (not limited to patent issues),&#xA;conditions are imposed on you (whether by court order, agreement or&#xA;otherwise) that contradict the conditions of this License, they do not&#xA;excuse you from the conditions of this License.  If you cannot&#xA;distribute so as to satisfy simultaneously your obligations under this&#xA;License and any other pertinent obligations, then as a consequence you&#xA;may not distribute the Library at all.  For example, if a patent&#xA;license would not permit royalty-free redistribution of the Library by&#xA;all those who receive copies directly or indirectly through you, then&#xA;the only way you could satisfy both it and this License would be to&#xA;refrain entirely from distribution of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;If any portion of this section is held invalid or unenforceable under any&#xA;particular circumstance, the balance of the section is intended to apply,&#xA;and the section as a whole is intended to apply in other circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;It is not the purpose of this section to induce you to infringe any&#xA;patents or other property right claims or to contest validity of any&#xA;such claims; this section has the sole purpose of protecting the&#xA;integrity of the free software distribution system which is&#xA;implemented by public license practices.  Many people have made&#xA;generous contributions to the wide range of software distributed&#xA;through that system in reliance on consistent application of that&#xA;system; it is up to the author/donor to decide if he or she is willing&#xA;to distribute software through any other system and a licensee cannot&#xA;impose that choice.&#xA;&#xA;This section is intended to make thoroughly clear what is believed to&#xA;be a consequence of the rest of this License.&#xA;&#xA;12. If the distribution and/or use of the Library is restricted in&#xA;certain countries either by patents or by copyrighted interfaces, the&#xA;original copyright holder who places the Library under this License may add&#xA;an explicit geographical distribution limitation excluding those countries,&#xA;so that distribution is permitted only in or among countries not thus&#xA;excluded.  In such case, this License incorporates the limitation as if&#xA;written in the body of this License.&#xA;&#xA;13. The Free Software Foundation may publish revised and/or new&#xA;versions of the Lesser General Public License from time to time.&#xA;Such new versions will be similar in spirit to the present version,&#xA;but may differ in detail to address new problems or concerns.&#xA;&#xA;Each version is given a distinguishing version number.  If the Library&#xA;specifies a version number of this License which applies to it and&#xA;&quot;any later version&quot;, you have the option of following the terms and&#xA;conditions either of that version or of any later version published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.  If the Library does not specify a&#xA;license version number, you may choose any version ever published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.&#xA;&#xA;14. If you wish to incorporate parts of the Library into other free&#xA;programs whose distribution conditions are incompatible with these,&#xA;write to the author to ask for permission.  For software which is&#xA;copyrighted by the Free Software Foundation, write to the Free&#xA;Software Foundation; we sometimes make exceptions for this.  Our&#xA;decision will be guided by the two goals of preserving the free status&#xA;of all derivatives of our free software and of promoting the sharing&#xA;and reuse of software generally.&#xA;&#xA;NO WARRANTY&#xA;&#xA;15. BECAUSE THE LIBRARY IS LICENSED FREE OF CHARGE, THERE IS NO&#xA;WARRANTY FOR THE LIBRARY, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW.&#xA;EXCEPT WHEN OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND/OR&#xA;OTHER PARTIES PROVIDE THE LIBRARY &quot;AS IS&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY&#xA;KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE&#xA;IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR&#xA;PURPOSE.  THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE&#xA;LIBRARY IS WITH YOU.  SHOULD THE LIBRARY PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME&#xA;THE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.&#xA;&#xA;16. IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN&#xA;WRITING WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MAY MODIFY&#xA;AND/OR REDISTRIBUTE THE LIBRARY AS PERMITTED ABOVE, BE LIABLE TO YOU&#xA;FOR DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR&#xA;CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE&#xA;LIBRARY (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF DATA OR DATA BEING&#xA;RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY YOU OR THIRD PARTIES OR A&#xA;FAILURE OF THE LIBRARY TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER SOFTWARE), EVEN IF&#xA;SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH&#xA;DAMAGES.&#xA;&#xA;END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS&#xA;&#xA;How to Apply These Terms to Your New Libraries&#xA;&#xA;If you develop a new library, and you want it to be of the greatest&#xA;possible use to the public, we recommend making it free software that&#xA;everyone can redistribute and change.  You can do so by permitting&#xA;redistribution under these terms (or, alternatively, under the terms of the&#xA;ordinary General Public License).&#xA;&#xA;To apply these terms, attach the following notices to the library.  It is&#xA;safest to attach them to the start of each source file to most effectively&#xA;convey the exclusion of warranty; and each file should have at least the&#xA;&quot;copyright&quot; line and a pointer to where the full notice is found.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;one line to give the library&apos;s name and a brief idea of what it does.&gt;&#xA;Copyright (C) &lt;year&gt;  &lt;name of author&gt;&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;&#xA;Also add information on how to contact you by electronic and paper mail.&#xA;&#xA;You should also get your employer (if you work as a programmer) or your&#xA;school, if any, to sign a &quot;copyright disclaimer&quot; for the library, if&#xA;necessary.  Here is a sample; alter the names:&#xA;&#xA;Yoyodyne, Inc., hereby disclaims all copyright interest in the&#xA;library `Frob&apos; (a library for tweaking knobs) written by James Random Hacker.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;signature of Ty Coon&gt;, 1 April 1990&#xA;Ty Coon, President of Vice&#xA;&#xA;That&apos;s all there is to it!'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='2'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.group' version='2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.localization' name='df_LT' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <requires size='3'>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.group' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr,2.1.7.3_v20070718-7B57e7TAXMAAqAqGr]'/>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.source' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070718,2.1.7.3_v20070718]'/>
        <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.jar' range='[2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs,2.1.7.3_v20070718-417C7CP1Bh_dDhQLBrBrHs]'>
          <filter>
            (org.eclipse.update.install.features=true)
          </filter>
        </required>
      </requires>
      <touchpoint id='null' version='0.0.0'/>
      <licenses size='1'>
        <license uri='%25licenseURL' url='%25licenseURL'>
          %license
        </license>
      </licenses>
      <copyright uri='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html' url='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html'>
        %copyright
      </copyright>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.source' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.source' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.4_v20071016)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.source' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.source' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.source' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.source&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.4_v20071016&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.jar' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg'>
      <properties size='10'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='%featureName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='%description'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description.url' value='http://www.rxtx.org'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.provider' value='%providerName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.update.feature.plugin' value='gnu.io.rxtx'/>
        <property name='df_LT.featureName' value='RXTX Extender SDK'/>
        <property name='df_LT.providerName' value='RXTX.org'/>
        <property name='df_LT.description' value='RXTX is a library to access serial ports from Java. The SDK Includes End-User Runtime and Source. '/>
        <property name='df_LT.copyright' value='Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.'/>
        <property name='df_LT.license' value='RXTX License v 2.1 - LGPL v 2.1 + Linking Over Controlled Interface.&#xA;RXTX is a native interface to serial ports in java.&#xA;&#xA;Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.&#xA;&#xA;A copy of the LGPL v 2.1 may be found at&#xA;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl.txt on March 4th 2007.  A copy is&#xA;included below for your convenience.&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;An executable that contains no derivative of any portion of RXTX, but&#xA;is designed to work with RXTX by being dynamically linked with it,&#xA;is considered a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; subject to the terms and&#xA;conditions of the GNU Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;The following has been added to the RXTX License to remove&#xA;any confusion about linking to RXTX.   We want to allow in part what&#xA;section 5, paragraph 2 of the LGPL does not permit in the special&#xA;case of linking over a controlled interface.  The intent is to add a&#xA;Java Specification Request or standards body defined interface in the&#xA;future as another exception but one is not currently available.&#xA;&#xA;http://www.fsf.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#LinkingOverControlledInterface&#xA;&#xA;As a special exception, the copyright holders of RXTX give you&#xA;permission to link RXTX with independent modules that communicate with&#xA;RXTX solely through the Sun Microsytems CommAPI interface version 2,&#xA;regardless of the license terms of these independent modules, and to copy&#xA;and distribute the resulting combined work under terms of your choice,&#xA;provided that every copy of the combined work is accompanied by a complete&#xA;copy of the source code of RXTX (the version of RXTX used to produce the&#xA;combined work), being distributed under the terms of the GNU Lesser General&#xA;Public License plus this exception.  An independent module is a&#xA;module which is not derived from or based on RXTX.&#xA;&#xA;Note that people who make modified versions of RXTX are not obligated&#xA;to grant this special exception for their modified versions; it is&#xA;their choice whether to do so.  The GNU Lesser General Public License&#xA;gives permission to release a modified version without this exception; this&#xA;exception also makes it possible to release a modified version which&#xA;carries forward this exception.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA&#xA;All trademarks belong to their respective owners.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;Version 2.1, February 1999&#xA;&#xA;Copyright (C) 1991, 1999 Free Software Foundation, Inc.&#xA;51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies&#xA;of this license document, but changing it is not allowed.&#xA;&#xA;[This is the first released version of the Lesser GPL.  It also counts&#xA;as the successor of the GNU Library Public License, version 2, hence&#xA;the version number 2.1.]&#xA;&#xA;Preamble&#xA;&#xA;The licenses for most software are designed to take away your&#xA;freedom to share and change it.  By contrast, the GNU General Public&#xA;Licenses are intended to guarantee your freedom to share and change&#xA;free software--to make sure the software is free for all its users.&#xA;&#xA;This license, the Lesser General Public License, applies to some&#xA;specially designated software packages--typically libraries--of the&#xA;Free Software Foundation and other authors who decide to use it.  You&#xA;can use it too, but we suggest you first think carefully about whether&#xA;this license or the ordinary General Public License is the better&#xA;strategy to use in any particular case, based on the explanations below.&#xA;&#xA;When we speak of free software, we are referring to freedom of use,&#xA;not price.  Our General Public Licenses are designed to make sure that&#xA;you have the freedom to distribute copies of free software (and charge&#xA;for this service if you wish); that you receive source code or can get&#xA;it if you want it; that you can change the software and use pieces of&#xA;it in new free programs; and that you are informed that you can do&#xA;these things.&#xA;&#xA;To protect your rights, we need to make restrictions that forbid&#xA;distributors to deny you these rights or to ask you to surrender these&#xA;rights.  These restrictions translate to certain responsibilities for&#xA;you if you distribute copies of the library or if you modify it.&#xA;&#xA;For example, if you distribute copies of the library, whether gratis&#xA;or for a fee, you must give the recipients all the rights that we gave&#xA;you.  You must make sure that they, too, receive or can get the source&#xA;code.  If you link other code with the library, you must provide&#xA;complete object files to the recipients, so that they can relink them&#xA;with the library after making changes to the library and recompiling&#xA;it.  And you must show them these terms so they know their rights.&#xA;&#xA;We protect your rights with a two-step method: (1) we copyright the&#xA;library, and (2) we offer you this license, which gives you legal&#xA;permission to copy, distribute and/or modify the library.&#xA;&#xA;To protect each distributor, we want to make it very clear that&#xA;there is no warranty for the free library.  Also, if the library is&#xA;modified by someone else and passed on, the recipients should know&#xA;that what they have is not the original version, so that the original&#xA;author&apos;s reputation will not be affected by problems that might be&#xA;introduced by others.&#xA;&#xA;Finally, software patents pose a constant threat to the existence of&#xA;any free program.  We wish to make sure that a company cannot&#xA;effectively restrict the users of a free program by obtaining a&#xA;restrictive license from a patent holder.  Therefore, we insist that&#xA;any patent license obtained for a version of the library must be&#xA;consistent with the full freedom of use specified in this license.&#xA;&#xA;Most GNU software, including some libraries, is covered by the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License.  This license, the GNU Lesser&#xA;General Public License, applies to certain designated libraries, and&#xA;is quite different from the ordinary General Public License.  We use&#xA;this license for certain libraries in order to permit linking those&#xA;libraries into non-free programs.&#xA;&#xA;When a program is linked with a library, whether statically or using&#xA;a shared library, the combination of the two is legally speaking a&#xA;combined work, a derivative of the original library.  The ordinary&#xA;General Public License therefore permits such linking only if the&#xA;entire combination fits its criteria of freedom.  The Lesser General&#xA;Public License permits more lax criteria for linking other code with&#xA;the library.&#xA;&#xA;We call this license the &quot;Lesser&quot; General Public License because it&#xA;does Less to protect the user&apos;s freedom than the ordinary General&#xA;Public License.  It also provides other free software developers Less&#xA;of an advantage over competing non-free programs.  These disadvantages&#xA;are the reason we use the ordinary General Public License for many&#xA;libraries.  However, the Lesser license provides advantages in certain&#xA;special circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;For example, on rare occasions, there may be a special need to&#xA;encourage the widest possible use of a certain library, so that it becomes&#xA;a de-facto standard.  To achieve this, non-free programs must be&#xA;allowed to use the library.  A more frequent case is that a free&#xA;library does the same job as widely used non-free libraries.  In this&#xA;case, there is little to gain by limiting the free library to free&#xA;software only, so we use the Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;In other cases, permission to use a particular library in non-free&#xA;programs enables a greater number of people to use a large body of&#xA;free software.  For example, permission to use the GNU C Library in&#xA;non-free programs enables many more people to use the whole GNU&#xA;operating system, as well as its variant, the GNU/Linux operating&#xA;system.&#xA;&#xA;Although the Lesser General Public License is Less protective of the&#xA;users&apos; freedom, it does ensure that the user of a program that is&#xA;linked with the Library has the freedom and the wherewithal to run&#xA;that program using a modified version of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;The precise terms and conditions for copying, distribution and&#xA;modification follow.  Pay close attention to the difference between a&#xA;&quot;work based on the library&quot; and a &quot;work that uses the library&quot;.  The&#xA;former contains code derived from the library, whereas the latter must&#xA;be combined with the library in order to run.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR COPYING, DISTRIBUTION AND MODIFICATION&#xA;&#xA;0. This License Agreement applies to any software library or other&#xA;program which contains a notice placed by the copyright holder or&#xA;other authorized party saying it may be distributed under the terms of&#xA;this Lesser General Public License (also called &quot;this License&quot;).&#xA;Each licensee is addressed as &quot;you&quot;.&#xA;&#xA;A &quot;library&quot; means a collection of software functions and/or data&#xA;prepared so as to be conveniently linked with application programs&#xA;(which use some of those functions and data) to form executables.&#xA;&#xA;The &quot;Library&quot;, below, refers to any such software library or work&#xA;which has been distributed under these terms.  A &quot;work based on the&#xA;Library&quot; means either the Library or any derivative work under&#xA;copyright law: that is to say, a work containing the Library or a&#xA;portion of it, either verbatim or with modifications and/or translated&#xA;straightforwardly into another language.  (Hereinafter, translation is&#xA;included without limitation in the term &quot;modification&quot;.)&#xA;&#xA;&quot;Source code&quot; for a work means the preferred form of the work for&#xA;making modifications to it.  For a library, complete source code means&#xA;all the source code for all modules it contains, plus any associated&#xA;interface definition files, plus the scripts used to control compilation&#xA;and installation of the library.&#xA;&#xA;Activities other than copying, distribution and modification are not&#xA;covered by this License; they are outside its scope.  The act of&#xA;running a program using the Library is not restricted, and output from&#xA;such a program is covered only if its contents constitute a work based&#xA;on the Library (independent of the use of the Library in a tool for&#xA;writing it).  Whether that is true depends on what the Library does&#xA;and what the program that uses the Library does.&#xA;&#xA;1. You may copy and distribute verbatim copies of the Library&apos;s&#xA;complete source code as you receive it, in any medium, provided that&#xA;you conspicuously and appropriately publish on each copy an&#xA;appropriate copyright notice and disclaimer of warranty; keep intact&#xA;all the notices that refer to this License and to the absence of any&#xA;warranty; and distribute a copy of this License along with the&#xA;Library.&#xA;&#xA;You may charge a fee for the physical act of transferring a copy,&#xA;and you may at your option offer warranty protection in exchange for a&#xA;fee.&#xA;&#xA;2. You may modify your copy or copies of the Library or any portion&#xA;of it, thus forming a work based on the Library, and copy and&#xA;distribute such modifications or work under the terms of Section 1&#xA;above, provided that you also meet all of these conditions:&#xA;&#xA;a) The modified work must itself be a software library.&#xA;&#xA;b) You must cause the files modified to carry prominent notices&#xA;stating that you changed the files and the date of any change.&#xA;&#xA;c) You must cause the whole of the work to be licensed at no&#xA;charge to all third parties under the terms of this License.&#xA;&#xA;d) If a facility in the modified Library refers to a function or a&#xA;table of data to be supplied by an application program that uses&#xA;the facility, other than as an argument passed when the facility&#xA;is invoked, then you must make a good faith effort to ensure that,&#xA;in the event an application does not supply such function or&#xA;table, the facility still operates, and performs whatever part of&#xA;its purpose remains meaningful.&#xA;&#xA;(For example, a function in a library to compute square roots has&#xA;a purpose that is entirely well-defined independent of the&#xA;application.  Therefore, Subsection 2d requires that any&#xA;application-supplied function or table used by this function must&#xA;be optional: if the application does not supply it, the square&#xA;root function must still compute square roots.)&#xA;&#xA;These requirements apply to the modified work as a whole.  If&#xA;identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Library,&#xA;and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in&#xA;themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those&#xA;sections when you distribute them as separate works.  But when you&#xA;distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based&#xA;on the Library, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of&#xA;this License, whose permissions for other licensees extend to the&#xA;entire whole, and thus to each and every part regardless of who wrote&#xA;it.&#xA;&#xA;Thus, it is not the intent of this section to claim rights or contest&#xA;your rights to work written entirely by you; rather, the intent is to&#xA;exercise the right to control the distribution of derivative or&#xA;collective works based on the Library.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, mere aggregation of another work not based on the Library&#xA;with the Library (or with a work based on the Library) on a volume of&#xA;a storage or distribution medium does not bring the other work under&#xA;the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;3. You may opt to apply the terms of the ordinary GNU General Public&#xA;License instead of this License to a given copy of the Library.  To do&#xA;this, you must alter all the notices that refer to this License, so&#xA;that they refer to the ordinary GNU General Public License, version 2,&#xA;instead of to this License.  (If a newer version than version 2 of the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License has appeared, then you can specify&#xA;that version instead if you wish.)  Do not make any other change in&#xA;these notices.&#xA;&#xA;Once this change is made in a given copy, it is irreversible for&#xA;that copy, so the ordinary GNU General Public License applies to all&#xA;subsequent copies and derivative works made from that copy.&#xA;&#xA;This option is useful when you wish to copy part of the code of&#xA;the Library into a program that is not a library.&#xA;&#xA;4. You may copy and distribute the Library (or a portion or&#xA;derivative of it, under Section 2) in object code or executable form&#xA;under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above provided that you accompany&#xA;it with the complete corresponding machine-readable source code, which&#xA;must be distributed under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above on a&#xA;medium customarily used for software interchange.&#xA;&#xA;If distribution of object code is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, then offering equivalent access to copy the&#xA;source code from the same place satisfies the requirement to&#xA;distribute the source code, even though third parties are not&#xA;compelled to copy the source along with the object code.&#xA;&#xA;5. A program that contains no derivative of any portion of the&#xA;Library, but is designed to work with the Library by being compiled or&#xA;linked with it, is called a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot;.  Such a&#xA;work, in isolation, is not a derivative work of the Library, and&#xA;therefore falls outside the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;However, linking a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library&#xA;creates an executable that is a derivative of the Library (because it&#xA;contains portions of the Library), rather than a &quot;work that uses the&#xA;library&quot;.  The executable is therefore covered by this License.&#xA;Section 6 states terms for distribution of such executables.&#xA;&#xA;When a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; uses material from a header file&#xA;that is part of the Library, the object code for the work may be a&#xA;derivative work of the Library even though the source code is not.&#xA;Whether this is true is especially significant if the work can be&#xA;linked without the Library, or if the work is itself a library.  The&#xA;threshold for this to be true is not precisely defined by law.&#xA;&#xA;If such an object file uses only numerical parameters, data&#xA;structure layouts and accessors, and small macros and small inline&#xA;functions (ten lines or less in length), then the use of the object&#xA;file is unrestricted, regardless of whether it is legally a derivative&#xA;work.  (Executables containing this object code plus portions of the&#xA;Library will still fall under Section 6.)&#xA;&#xA;Otherwise, if the work is a derivative of the Library, you may&#xA;distribute the object code for the work under the terms of Section 6.&#xA;Any executables containing that work also fall under Section 6,&#xA;whether or not they are linked directly with the Library itself.&#xA;&#xA;6. As an exception to the Sections above, you may also combine or&#xA;link a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library to produce a&#xA;work containing portions of the Library, and distribute that work&#xA;under terms of your choice, provided that the terms permit&#xA;modification of the work for the customer&apos;s own use and reverse&#xA;engineering for debugging such modifications.&#xA;&#xA;You must give prominent notice with each copy of the work that the&#xA;Library is used in it and that the Library and its use are covered by&#xA;this License.  You must supply a copy of this License.  If the work&#xA;during execution displays copyright notices, you must include the&#xA;copyright notice for the Library among them, as well as a reference&#xA;directing the user to the copy of this License.  Also, you must do one&#xA;of these things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the work with the complete corresponding&#xA;machine-readable source code for the Library including whatever&#xA;changes were used in the work (which must be distributed under&#xA;Sections 1 and 2 above); and, if the work is an executable linked&#xA;with the Library, with the complete machine-readable &quot;work that&#xA;uses the Library&quot;, as object code and/or source code, so that the&#xA;user can modify the Library and then relink to produce a modified&#xA;executable containing the modified Library.  (It is understood&#xA;that the user who changes the contents of definitions files in the&#xA;Library will not necessarily be able to recompile the application&#xA;to use the modified definitions.)&#xA;&#xA;b) Use a suitable shared library mechanism for linking with the&#xA;Library.  A suitable mechanism is one that (1) uses at run time a&#xA;copy of the library already present on the user&apos;s computer system,&#xA;rather than copying library functions into the executable, and (2)&#xA;will operate properly with a modified version of the library, if&#xA;the user installs one, as long as the modified version is&#xA;interface-compatible with the version that the work was made with.&#xA;&#xA;c) Accompany the work with a written offer, valid for at&#xA;least three years, to give the same user the materials&#xA;specified in Subsection 6a, above, for a charge no more&#xA;than the cost of performing this distribution.&#xA;&#xA;d) If distribution of the work is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, offer equivalent access to copy the above&#xA;specified materials from the same place.&#xA;&#xA;e) Verify that the user has already received a copy of these&#xA;materials or that you have already sent this user a copy.&#xA;&#xA;For an executable, the required form of the &quot;work that uses the&#xA;Library&quot; must include any data and utility programs needed for&#xA;reproducing the executable from it.  However, as a special exception,&#xA;the materials to be distributed need not include anything that is&#xA;normally distributed (in either source or binary form) with the major&#xA;components (compiler, kernel, and so on) of the operating system on&#xA;which the executable runs, unless that component itself accompanies&#xA;the executable.&#xA;&#xA;It may happen that this requirement contradicts the license&#xA;restrictions of other proprietary libraries that do not normally&#xA;accompany the operating system.  Such a contradiction means you cannot&#xA;use both them and the Library together in an executable that you&#xA;distribute.&#xA;&#xA;7. You may place library facilities that are a work based on the&#xA;Library side-by-side in a single library together with other library&#xA;facilities not covered by this License, and distribute such a combined&#xA;library, provided that the separate distribution of the work based on&#xA;the Library and of the other library facilities is otherwise&#xA;permitted, and provided that you do these two things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the combined library with a copy of the same work&#xA;based on the Library, uncombined with any other library&#xA;facilities.  This must be distributed under the terms of the&#xA;Sections above.&#xA;&#xA;b) Give prominent notice with the combined library of the fact&#xA;that part of it is a work based on the Library, and explaining&#xA;where to find the accompanying uncombined form of the same work.&#xA;&#xA;8. You may not copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or distribute&#xA;the Library except as expressly provided under this License.  Any&#xA;attempt otherwise to copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or&#xA;distribute the Library is void, and will automatically terminate your&#xA;rights under this License.  However, parties who have received copies,&#xA;or rights, from you under this License will not have their licenses&#xA;terminated so long as such parties remain in full compliance.&#xA;&#xA;9. You are not required to accept this License, since you have not&#xA;signed it.  However, nothing else grants you permission to modify or&#xA;distribute the Library or its derivative works.  These actions are&#xA;prohibited by law if you do not accept this License.  Therefore, by&#xA;modifying or distributing the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), you indicate your acceptance of this License to do so, and&#xA;all its terms and conditions for copying, distributing or modifying&#xA;the Library or works based on it.&#xA;&#xA;10. Each time you redistribute the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), the recipient automatically receives a license from the&#xA;original licensor to copy, distribute, link with or modify the Library&#xA;subject to these terms and conditions.  You may not impose any further&#xA;restrictions on the recipients&apos; exercise of the rights granted herein.&#xA;You are not responsible for enforcing compliance by third parties with&#xA;this License.&#xA;&#xA;11. If, as a consequence of a court judgment or allegation of patent&#xA;infringement or for any other reason (not limited to patent issues),&#xA;conditions are imposed on you (whether by court order, agreement or&#xA;otherwise) that contradict the conditions of this License, they do not&#xA;excuse you from the conditions of this License.  If you cannot&#xA;distribute so as to satisfy simultaneously your obligations under this&#xA;License and any other pertinent obligations, then as a consequence you&#xA;may not distribute the Library at all.  For example, if a patent&#xA;license would not permit royalty-free redistribution of the Library by&#xA;all those who receive copies directly or indirectly through you, then&#xA;the only way you could satisfy both it and this License would be to&#xA;refrain entirely from distribution of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;If any portion of this section is held invalid or unenforceable under any&#xA;particular circumstance, the balance of the section is intended to apply,&#xA;and the section as a whole is intended to apply in other circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;It is not the purpose of this section to induce you to infringe any&#xA;patents or other property right claims or to contest validity of any&#xA;such claims; this section has the sole purpose of protecting the&#xA;integrity of the free software distribution system which is&#xA;implemented by public license practices.  Many people have made&#xA;generous contributions to the wide range of software distributed&#xA;through that system in reliance on consistent application of that&#xA;system; it is up to the author/donor to decide if he or she is willing&#xA;to distribute software through any other system and a licensee cannot&#xA;impose that choice.&#xA;&#xA;This section is intended to make thoroughly clear what is believed to&#xA;be a consequence of the rest of this License.&#xA;&#xA;12. If the distribution and/or use of the Library is restricted in&#xA;certain countries either by patents or by copyrighted interfaces, the&#xA;original copyright holder who places the Library under this License may add&#xA;an explicit geographical distribution limitation excluding those countries,&#xA;so that distribution is permitted only in or among countries not thus&#xA;excluded.  In such case, this License incorporates the limitation as if&#xA;written in the body of this License.&#xA;&#xA;13. The Free Software Foundation may publish revised and/or new&#xA;versions of the Lesser General Public License from time to time.&#xA;Such new versions will be similar in spirit to the present version,&#xA;but may differ in detail to address new problems or concerns.&#xA;&#xA;Each version is given a distinguishing version number.  If the Library&#xA;specifies a version number of this License which applies to it and&#xA;&quot;any later version&quot;, you have the option of following the terms and&#xA;conditions either of that version or of any later version published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.  If the Library does not specify a&#xA;license version number, you may choose any version ever published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.&#xA;&#xA;14. If you wish to incorporate parts of the Library into other free&#xA;programs whose distribution conditions are incompatible with these,&#xA;write to the author to ask for permission.  For software which is&#xA;copyrighted by the Free Software Foundation, write to the Free&#xA;Software Foundation; we sometimes make exceptions for this.  Our&#xA;decision will be guided by the two goals of preserving the free status&#xA;of all derivatives of our free software and of promoting the sharing&#xA;and reuse of software generally.&#xA;&#xA;NO WARRANTY&#xA;&#xA;15. BECAUSE THE LIBRARY IS LICENSED FREE OF CHARGE, THERE IS NO&#xA;WARRANTY FOR THE LIBRARY, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW.&#xA;EXCEPT WHEN OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND/OR&#xA;OTHER PARTIES PROVIDE THE LIBRARY &quot;AS IS&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY&#xA;KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE&#xA;IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR&#xA;PURPOSE.  THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE&#xA;LIBRARY IS WITH YOU.  SHOULD THE LIBRARY PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME&#xA;THE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.&#xA;&#xA;16. IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN&#xA;WRITING WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MAY MODIFY&#xA;AND/OR REDISTRIBUTE THE LIBRARY AS PERMITTED ABOVE, BE LIABLE TO YOU&#xA;FOR DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR&#xA;CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE&#xA;LIBRARY (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF DATA OR DATA BEING&#xA;RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY YOU OR THIRD PARTIES OR A&#xA;FAILURE OF THE LIBRARY TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER SOFTWARE), EVEN IF&#xA;SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH&#xA;DAMAGES.&#xA;&#xA;END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS&#xA;&#xA;How to Apply These Terms to Your New Libraries&#xA;&#xA;If you develop a new library, and you want it to be of the greatest&#xA;possible use to the public, we recommend making it free software that&#xA;everyone can redistribute and change.  You can do so by permitting&#xA;redistribution under these terms (or, alternatively, under the terms of the&#xA;ordinary General Public License).&#xA;&#xA;To apply these terms, attach the following notices to the library.  It is&#xA;safest to attach them to the start of each source file to most effectively&#xA;convey the exclusion of warranty; and each file should have at least the&#xA;&quot;copyright&quot; line and a pointer to where the full notice is found.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;one line to give the library&apos;s name and a brief idea of what it does.&gt;&#xA;Copyright (C) &lt;year&gt;  &lt;name of author&gt;&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;&#xA;Also add information on how to contact you by electronic and paper mail.&#xA;&#xA;You should also get your employer (if you work as a programmer) or your&#xA;school, if any, to sign a &quot;copyright disclaimer&quot; for the library, if&#xA;necessary.  Here is a sample; alter the names:&#xA;&#xA;Yoyodyne, Inc., hereby disclaims all copyright interest in the&#xA;library `Frob&apos; (a library for tweaking knobs) written by James Random Hacker.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;signature of Ty Coon&gt;, 1 April 1990&#xA;Ty Coon, President of Vice&#xA;&#xA;That&apos;s all there is to it!'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk.feature.jar' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='feature' version='1.0.0'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.update.feature' name='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg'/>
      </provides>
      <filter>
        (org.eclipse.update.install.features=true)
      </filter>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='org.eclipse.update.feature' id='gnu.io.rxtx.sdk' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-417C7DP1Bh_eEaQJBrHBHg'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='1'>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
      <licenses size='1'>
        <license uri='%25licenseURL' url='%25licenseURL'>
          %license
        </license>
      </licenses>
      <copyright uri='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html' url='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html'>
        %copyright
      </copyright>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.jar' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf'>
      <properties size='10'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='%featureName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='%description'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description.url' value='http://www.rxtx.org'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.provider' value='%providerName'/>
        <property name='org.eclipse.update.feature.plugin' value='gnu.io.rxtx'/>
        <property name='df_LT.featureName' value='RXTX End-User Runtime'/>
        <property name='df_LT.providerName' value='RXTX.org'/>
        <property name='df_LT.description' value='RXTX is a library to access serial ports from Java. '/>
        <property name='df_LT.copyright' value='Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.'/>
        <property name='df_LT.license' value='RXTX License v 2.1 - LGPL v 2.1 + Linking Over Controlled Interface.&#xA;RXTX is a native interface to serial ports in java.&#xA;&#xA;Copyright 1997-2007 by Trent Jarvi tjarvi@qbang.org and others who&#xA;actually wrote it.  See individual source files for more information.&#xA;&#xA;A copy of the LGPL v 2.1 may be found at&#xA;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl.txt on March 4th 2007.  A copy is&#xA;included below for your convenience.&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;An executable that contains no derivative of any portion of RXTX, but&#xA;is designed to work with RXTX by being dynamically linked with it,&#xA;is considered a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; subject to the terms and&#xA;conditions of the GNU Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;The following has been added to the RXTX License to remove&#xA;any confusion about linking to RXTX.   We want to allow in part what&#xA;section 5, paragraph 2 of the LGPL does not permit in the special&#xA;case of linking over a controlled interface.  The intent is to add a&#xA;Java Specification Request or standards body defined interface in the&#xA;future as another exception but one is not currently available.&#xA;&#xA;http://www.fsf.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#LinkingOverControlledInterface&#xA;&#xA;As a special exception, the copyright holders of RXTX give you&#xA;permission to link RXTX with independent modules that communicate with&#xA;RXTX solely through the Sun Microsytems CommAPI interface version 2,&#xA;regardless of the license terms of these independent modules, and to copy&#xA;and distribute the resulting combined work under terms of your choice,&#xA;provided that every copy of the combined work is accompanied by a complete&#xA;copy of the source code of RXTX (the version of RXTX used to produce the&#xA;combined work), being distributed under the terms of the GNU Lesser General&#xA;Public License plus this exception.  An independent module is a&#xA;module which is not derived from or based on RXTX.&#xA;&#xA;Note that people who make modified versions of RXTX are not obligated&#xA;to grant this special exception for their modified versions; it is&#xA;their choice whether to do so.  The GNU Lesser General Public License&#xA;gives permission to release a modified version without this exception; this&#xA;exception also makes it possible to release a modified version which&#xA;carries forward this exception.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA&#xA;All trademarks belong to their respective owners.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;Version 2.1, February 1999&#xA;&#xA;Copyright (C) 1991, 1999 Free Software Foundation, Inc.&#xA;51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies&#xA;of this license document, but changing it is not allowed.&#xA;&#xA;[This is the first released version of the Lesser GPL.  It also counts&#xA;as the successor of the GNU Library Public License, version 2, hence&#xA;the version number 2.1.]&#xA;&#xA;Preamble&#xA;&#xA;The licenses for most software are designed to take away your&#xA;freedom to share and change it.  By contrast, the GNU General Public&#xA;Licenses are intended to guarantee your freedom to share and change&#xA;free software--to make sure the software is free for all its users.&#xA;&#xA;This license, the Lesser General Public License, applies to some&#xA;specially designated software packages--typically libraries--of the&#xA;Free Software Foundation and other authors who decide to use it.  You&#xA;can use it too, but we suggest you first think carefully about whether&#xA;this license or the ordinary General Public License is the better&#xA;strategy to use in any particular case, based on the explanations below.&#xA;&#xA;When we speak of free software, we are referring to freedom of use,&#xA;not price.  Our General Public Licenses are designed to make sure that&#xA;you have the freedom to distribute copies of free software (and charge&#xA;for this service if you wish); that you receive source code or can get&#xA;it if you want it; that you can change the software and use pieces of&#xA;it in new free programs; and that you are informed that you can do&#xA;these things.&#xA;&#xA;To protect your rights, we need to make restrictions that forbid&#xA;distributors to deny you these rights or to ask you to surrender these&#xA;rights.  These restrictions translate to certain responsibilities for&#xA;you if you distribute copies of the library or if you modify it.&#xA;&#xA;For example, if you distribute copies of the library, whether gratis&#xA;or for a fee, you must give the recipients all the rights that we gave&#xA;you.  You must make sure that they, too, receive or can get the source&#xA;code.  If you link other code with the library, you must provide&#xA;complete object files to the recipients, so that they can relink them&#xA;with the library after making changes to the library and recompiling&#xA;it.  And you must show them these terms so they know their rights.&#xA;&#xA;We protect your rights with a two-step method: (1) we copyright the&#xA;library, and (2) we offer you this license, which gives you legal&#xA;permission to copy, distribute and/or modify the library.&#xA;&#xA;To protect each distributor, we want to make it very clear that&#xA;there is no warranty for the free library.  Also, if the library is&#xA;modified by someone else and passed on, the recipients should know&#xA;that what they have is not the original version, so that the original&#xA;author&apos;s reputation will not be affected by problems that might be&#xA;introduced by others.&#xA;&#xA;Finally, software patents pose a constant threat to the existence of&#xA;any free program.  We wish to make sure that a company cannot&#xA;effectively restrict the users of a free program by obtaining a&#xA;restrictive license from a patent holder.  Therefore, we insist that&#xA;any patent license obtained for a version of the library must be&#xA;consistent with the full freedom of use specified in this license.&#xA;&#xA;Most GNU software, including some libraries, is covered by the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License.  This license, the GNU Lesser&#xA;General Public License, applies to certain designated libraries, and&#xA;is quite different from the ordinary General Public License.  We use&#xA;this license for certain libraries in order to permit linking those&#xA;libraries into non-free programs.&#xA;&#xA;When a program is linked with a library, whether statically or using&#xA;a shared library, the combination of the two is legally speaking a&#xA;combined work, a derivative of the original library.  The ordinary&#xA;General Public License therefore permits such linking only if the&#xA;entire combination fits its criteria of freedom.  The Lesser General&#xA;Public License permits more lax criteria for linking other code with&#xA;the library.&#xA;&#xA;We call this license the &quot;Lesser&quot; General Public License because it&#xA;does Less to protect the user&apos;s freedom than the ordinary General&#xA;Public License.  It also provides other free software developers Less&#xA;of an advantage over competing non-free programs.  These disadvantages&#xA;are the reason we use the ordinary General Public License for many&#xA;libraries.  However, the Lesser license provides advantages in certain&#xA;special circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;For example, on rare occasions, there may be a special need to&#xA;encourage the widest possible use of a certain library, so that it becomes&#xA;a de-facto standard.  To achieve this, non-free programs must be&#xA;allowed to use the library.  A more frequent case is that a free&#xA;library does the same job as widely used non-free libraries.  In this&#xA;case, there is little to gain by limiting the free library to free&#xA;software only, so we use the Lesser General Public License.&#xA;&#xA;In other cases, permission to use a particular library in non-free&#xA;programs enables a greater number of people to use a large body of&#xA;free software.  For example, permission to use the GNU C Library in&#xA;non-free programs enables many more people to use the whole GNU&#xA;operating system, as well as its variant, the GNU/Linux operating&#xA;system.&#xA;&#xA;Although the Lesser General Public License is Less protective of the&#xA;users&apos; freedom, it does ensure that the user of a program that is&#xA;linked with the Library has the freedom and the wherewithal to run&#xA;that program using a modified version of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;The precise terms and conditions for copying, distribution and&#xA;modification follow.  Pay close attention to the difference between a&#xA;&quot;work based on the library&quot; and a &quot;work that uses the library&quot;.  The&#xA;former contains code derived from the library, whereas the latter must&#xA;be combined with the library in order to run.&#xA;&#xA;GNU LESSER GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE&#xA;TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR COPYING, DISTRIBUTION AND MODIFICATION&#xA;&#xA;0. This License Agreement applies to any software library or other&#xA;program which contains a notice placed by the copyright holder or&#xA;other authorized party saying it may be distributed under the terms of&#xA;this Lesser General Public License (also called &quot;this License&quot;).&#xA;Each licensee is addressed as &quot;you&quot;.&#xA;&#xA;A &quot;library&quot; means a collection of software functions and/or data&#xA;prepared so as to be conveniently linked with application programs&#xA;(which use some of those functions and data) to form executables.&#xA;&#xA;The &quot;Library&quot;, below, refers to any such software library or work&#xA;which has been distributed under these terms.  A &quot;work based on the&#xA;Library&quot; means either the Library or any derivative work under&#xA;copyright law: that is to say, a work containing the Library or a&#xA;portion of it, either verbatim or with modifications and/or translated&#xA;straightforwardly into another language.  (Hereinafter, translation is&#xA;included without limitation in the term &quot;modification&quot;.)&#xA;&#xA;&quot;Source code&quot; for a work means the preferred form of the work for&#xA;making modifications to it.  For a library, complete source code means&#xA;all the source code for all modules it contains, plus any associated&#xA;interface definition files, plus the scripts used to control compilation&#xA;and installation of the library.&#xA;&#xA;Activities other than copying, distribution and modification are not&#xA;covered by this License; they are outside its scope.  The act of&#xA;running a program using the Library is not restricted, and output from&#xA;such a program is covered only if its contents constitute a work based&#xA;on the Library (independent of the use of the Library in a tool for&#xA;writing it).  Whether that is true depends on what the Library does&#xA;and what the program that uses the Library does.&#xA;&#xA;1. You may copy and distribute verbatim copies of the Library&apos;s&#xA;complete source code as you receive it, in any medium, provided that&#xA;you conspicuously and appropriately publish on each copy an&#xA;appropriate copyright notice and disclaimer of warranty; keep intact&#xA;all the notices that refer to this License and to the absence of any&#xA;warranty; and distribute a copy of this License along with the&#xA;Library.&#xA;&#xA;You may charge a fee for the physical act of transferring a copy,&#xA;and you may at your option offer warranty protection in exchange for a&#xA;fee.&#xA;&#xA;2. You may modify your copy or copies of the Library or any portion&#xA;of it, thus forming a work based on the Library, and copy and&#xA;distribute such modifications or work under the terms of Section 1&#xA;above, provided that you also meet all of these conditions:&#xA;&#xA;a) The modified work must itself be a software library.&#xA;&#xA;b) You must cause the files modified to carry prominent notices&#xA;stating that you changed the files and the date of any change.&#xA;&#xA;c) You must cause the whole of the work to be licensed at no&#xA;charge to all third parties under the terms of this License.&#xA;&#xA;d) If a facility in the modified Library refers to a function or a&#xA;table of data to be supplied by an application program that uses&#xA;the facility, other than as an argument passed when the facility&#xA;is invoked, then you must make a good faith effort to ensure that,&#xA;in the event an application does not supply such function or&#xA;table, the facility still operates, and performs whatever part of&#xA;its purpose remains meaningful.&#xA;&#xA;(For example, a function in a library to compute square roots has&#xA;a purpose that is entirely well-defined independent of the&#xA;application.  Therefore, Subsection 2d requires that any&#xA;application-supplied function or table used by this function must&#xA;be optional: if the application does not supply it, the square&#xA;root function must still compute square roots.)&#xA;&#xA;These requirements apply to the modified work as a whole.  If&#xA;identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Library,&#xA;and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in&#xA;themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those&#xA;sections when you distribute them as separate works.  But when you&#xA;distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based&#xA;on the Library, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of&#xA;this License, whose permissions for other licensees extend to the&#xA;entire whole, and thus to each and every part regardless of who wrote&#xA;it.&#xA;&#xA;Thus, it is not the intent of this section to claim rights or contest&#xA;your rights to work written entirely by you; rather, the intent is to&#xA;exercise the right to control the distribution of derivative or&#xA;collective works based on the Library.&#xA;&#xA;In addition, mere aggregation of another work not based on the Library&#xA;with the Library (or with a work based on the Library) on a volume of&#xA;a storage or distribution medium does not bring the other work under&#xA;the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;3. You may opt to apply the terms of the ordinary GNU General Public&#xA;License instead of this License to a given copy of the Library.  To do&#xA;this, you must alter all the notices that refer to this License, so&#xA;that they refer to the ordinary GNU General Public License, version 2,&#xA;instead of to this License.  (If a newer version than version 2 of the&#xA;ordinary GNU General Public License has appeared, then you can specify&#xA;that version instead if you wish.)  Do not make any other change in&#xA;these notices.&#xA;&#xA;Once this change is made in a given copy, it is irreversible for&#xA;that copy, so the ordinary GNU General Public License applies to all&#xA;subsequent copies and derivative works made from that copy.&#xA;&#xA;This option is useful when you wish to copy part of the code of&#xA;the Library into a program that is not a library.&#xA;&#xA;4. You may copy and distribute the Library (or a portion or&#xA;derivative of it, under Section 2) in object code or executable form&#xA;under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above provided that you accompany&#xA;it with the complete corresponding machine-readable source code, which&#xA;must be distributed under the terms of Sections 1 and 2 above on a&#xA;medium customarily used for software interchange.&#xA;&#xA;If distribution of object code is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, then offering equivalent access to copy the&#xA;source code from the same place satisfies the requirement to&#xA;distribute the source code, even though third parties are not&#xA;compelled to copy the source along with the object code.&#xA;&#xA;5. A program that contains no derivative of any portion of the&#xA;Library, but is designed to work with the Library by being compiled or&#xA;linked with it, is called a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot;.  Such a&#xA;work, in isolation, is not a derivative work of the Library, and&#xA;therefore falls outside the scope of this License.&#xA;&#xA;However, linking a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library&#xA;creates an executable that is a derivative of the Library (because it&#xA;contains portions of the Library), rather than a &quot;work that uses the&#xA;library&quot;.  The executable is therefore covered by this License.&#xA;Section 6 states terms for distribution of such executables.&#xA;&#xA;When a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; uses material from a header file&#xA;that is part of the Library, the object code for the work may be a&#xA;derivative work of the Library even though the source code is not.&#xA;Whether this is true is especially significant if the work can be&#xA;linked without the Library, or if the work is itself a library.  The&#xA;threshold for this to be true is not precisely defined by law.&#xA;&#xA;If such an object file uses only numerical parameters, data&#xA;structure layouts and accessors, and small macros and small inline&#xA;functions (ten lines or less in length), then the use of the object&#xA;file is unrestricted, regardless of whether it is legally a derivative&#xA;work.  (Executables containing this object code plus portions of the&#xA;Library will still fall under Section 6.)&#xA;&#xA;Otherwise, if the work is a derivative of the Library, you may&#xA;distribute the object code for the work under the terms of Section 6.&#xA;Any executables containing that work also fall under Section 6,&#xA;whether or not they are linked directly with the Library itself.&#xA;&#xA;6. As an exception to the Sections above, you may also combine or&#xA;link a &quot;work that uses the Library&quot; with the Library to produce a&#xA;work containing portions of the Library, and distribute that work&#xA;under terms of your choice, provided that the terms permit&#xA;modification of the work for the customer&apos;s own use and reverse&#xA;engineering for debugging such modifications.&#xA;&#xA;You must give prominent notice with each copy of the work that the&#xA;Library is used in it and that the Library and its use are covered by&#xA;this License.  You must supply a copy of this License.  If the work&#xA;during execution displays copyright notices, you must include the&#xA;copyright notice for the Library among them, as well as a reference&#xA;directing the user to the copy of this License.  Also, you must do one&#xA;of these things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the work with the complete corresponding&#xA;machine-readable source code for the Library including whatever&#xA;changes were used in the work (which must be distributed under&#xA;Sections 1 and 2 above); and, if the work is an executable linked&#xA;with the Library, with the complete machine-readable &quot;work that&#xA;uses the Library&quot;, as object code and/or source code, so that the&#xA;user can modify the Library and then relink to produce a modified&#xA;executable containing the modified Library.  (It is understood&#xA;that the user who changes the contents of definitions files in the&#xA;Library will not necessarily be able to recompile the application&#xA;to use the modified definitions.)&#xA;&#xA;b) Use a suitable shared library mechanism for linking with the&#xA;Library.  A suitable mechanism is one that (1) uses at run time a&#xA;copy of the library already present on the user&apos;s computer system,&#xA;rather than copying library functions into the executable, and (2)&#xA;will operate properly with a modified version of the library, if&#xA;the user installs one, as long as the modified version is&#xA;interface-compatible with the version that the work was made with.&#xA;&#xA;c) Accompany the work with a written offer, valid for at&#xA;least three years, to give the same user the materials&#xA;specified in Subsection 6a, above, for a charge no more&#xA;than the cost of performing this distribution.&#xA;&#xA;d) If distribution of the work is made by offering access to copy&#xA;from a designated place, offer equivalent access to copy the above&#xA;specified materials from the same place.&#xA;&#xA;e) Verify that the user has already received a copy of these&#xA;materials or that you have already sent this user a copy.&#xA;&#xA;For an executable, the required form of the &quot;work that uses the&#xA;Library&quot; must include any data and utility programs needed for&#xA;reproducing the executable from it.  However, as a special exception,&#xA;the materials to be distributed need not include anything that is&#xA;normally distributed (in either source or binary form) with the major&#xA;components (compiler, kernel, and so on) of the operating system on&#xA;which the executable runs, unless that component itself accompanies&#xA;the executable.&#xA;&#xA;It may happen that this requirement contradicts the license&#xA;restrictions of other proprietary libraries that do not normally&#xA;accompany the operating system.  Such a contradiction means you cannot&#xA;use both them and the Library together in an executable that you&#xA;distribute.&#xA;&#xA;7. You may place library facilities that are a work based on the&#xA;Library side-by-side in a single library together with other library&#xA;facilities not covered by this License, and distribute such a combined&#xA;library, provided that the separate distribution of the work based on&#xA;the Library and of the other library facilities is otherwise&#xA;permitted, and provided that you do these two things:&#xA;&#xA;a) Accompany the combined library with a copy of the same work&#xA;based on the Library, uncombined with any other library&#xA;facilities.  This must be distributed under the terms of the&#xA;Sections above.&#xA;&#xA;b) Give prominent notice with the combined library of the fact&#xA;that part of it is a work based on the Library, and explaining&#xA;where to find the accompanying uncombined form of the same work.&#xA;&#xA;8. You may not copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or distribute&#xA;the Library except as expressly provided under this License.  Any&#xA;attempt otherwise to copy, modify, sublicense, link with, or&#xA;distribute the Library is void, and will automatically terminate your&#xA;rights under this License.  However, parties who have received copies,&#xA;or rights, from you under this License will not have their licenses&#xA;terminated so long as such parties remain in full compliance.&#xA;&#xA;9. You are not required to accept this License, since you have not&#xA;signed it.  However, nothing else grants you permission to modify or&#xA;distribute the Library or its derivative works.  These actions are&#xA;prohibited by law if you do not accept this License.  Therefore, by&#xA;modifying or distributing the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), you indicate your acceptance of this License to do so, and&#xA;all its terms and conditions for copying, distributing or modifying&#xA;the Library or works based on it.&#xA;&#xA;10. Each time you redistribute the Library (or any work based on the&#xA;Library), the recipient automatically receives a license from the&#xA;original licensor to copy, distribute, link with or modify the Library&#xA;subject to these terms and conditions.  You may not impose any further&#xA;restrictions on the recipients&apos; exercise of the rights granted herein.&#xA;You are not responsible for enforcing compliance by third parties with&#xA;this License.&#xA;&#xA;11. If, as a consequence of a court judgment or allegation of patent&#xA;infringement or for any other reason (not limited to patent issues),&#xA;conditions are imposed on you (whether by court order, agreement or&#xA;otherwise) that contradict the conditions of this License, they do not&#xA;excuse you from the conditions of this License.  If you cannot&#xA;distribute so as to satisfy simultaneously your obligations under this&#xA;License and any other pertinent obligations, then as a consequence you&#xA;may not distribute the Library at all.  For example, if a patent&#xA;license would not permit royalty-free redistribution of the Library by&#xA;all those who receive copies directly or indirectly through you, then&#xA;the only way you could satisfy both it and this License would be to&#xA;refrain entirely from distribution of the Library.&#xA;&#xA;If any portion of this section is held invalid or unenforceable under any&#xA;particular circumstance, the balance of the section is intended to apply,&#xA;and the section as a whole is intended to apply in other circumstances.&#xA;&#xA;It is not the purpose of this section to induce you to infringe any&#xA;patents or other property right claims or to contest validity of any&#xA;such claims; this section has the sole purpose of protecting the&#xA;integrity of the free software distribution system which is&#xA;implemented by public license practices.  Many people have made&#xA;generous contributions to the wide range of software distributed&#xA;through that system in reliance on consistent application of that&#xA;system; it is up to the author/donor to decide if he or she is willing&#xA;to distribute software through any other system and a licensee cannot&#xA;impose that choice.&#xA;&#xA;This section is intended to make thoroughly clear what is believed to&#xA;be a consequence of the rest of this License.&#xA;&#xA;12. If the distribution and/or use of the Library is restricted in&#xA;certain countries either by patents or by copyrighted interfaces, the&#xA;original copyright holder who places the Library under this License may add&#xA;an explicit geographical distribution limitation excluding those countries,&#xA;so that distribution is permitted only in or among countries not thus&#xA;excluded.  In such case, this License incorporates the limitation as if&#xA;written in the body of this License.&#xA;&#xA;13. The Free Software Foundation may publish revised and/or new&#xA;versions of the Lesser General Public License from time to time.&#xA;Such new versions will be similar in spirit to the present version,&#xA;but may differ in detail to address new problems or concerns.&#xA;&#xA;Each version is given a distinguishing version number.  If the Library&#xA;specifies a version number of this License which applies to it and&#xA;&quot;any later version&quot;, you have the option of following the terms and&#xA;conditions either of that version or of any later version published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.  If the Library does not specify a&#xA;license version number, you may choose any version ever published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation.&#xA;&#xA;14. If you wish to incorporate parts of the Library into other free&#xA;programs whose distribution conditions are incompatible with these,&#xA;write to the author to ask for permission.  For software which is&#xA;copyrighted by the Free Software Foundation, write to the Free&#xA;Software Foundation; we sometimes make exceptions for this.  Our&#xA;decision will be guided by the two goals of preserving the free status&#xA;of all derivatives of our free software and of promoting the sharing&#xA;and reuse of software generally.&#xA;&#xA;NO WARRANTY&#xA;&#xA;15. BECAUSE THE LIBRARY IS LICENSED FREE OF CHARGE, THERE IS NO&#xA;WARRANTY FOR THE LIBRARY, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW.&#xA;EXCEPT WHEN OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND/OR&#xA;OTHER PARTIES PROVIDE THE LIBRARY &quot;AS IS&quot; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY&#xA;KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE&#xA;IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR&#xA;PURPOSE.  THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE&#xA;LIBRARY IS WITH YOU.  SHOULD THE LIBRARY PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME&#xA;THE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.&#xA;&#xA;16. IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN&#xA;WRITING WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MAY MODIFY&#xA;AND/OR REDISTRIBUTE THE LIBRARY AS PERMITTED ABOVE, BE LIABLE TO YOU&#xA;FOR DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR&#xA;CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE&#xA;LIBRARY (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF DATA OR DATA BEING&#xA;RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY YOU OR THIRD PARTIES OR A&#xA;FAILURE OF THE LIBRARY TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER SOFTWARE), EVEN IF&#xA;SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH&#xA;DAMAGES.&#xA;&#xA;END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS&#xA;&#xA;How to Apply These Terms to Your New Libraries&#xA;&#xA;If you develop a new library, and you want it to be of the greatest&#xA;possible use to the public, we recommend making it free software that&#xA;everyone can redistribute and change.  You can do so by permitting&#xA;redistribution under these terms (or, alternatively, under the terms of the&#xA;ordinary General Public License).&#xA;&#xA;To apply these terms, attach the following notices to the library.  It is&#xA;safest to attach them to the start of each source file to most effectively&#xA;convey the exclusion of warranty; and each file should have at least the&#xA;&quot;copyright&quot; line and a pointer to where the full notice is found.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;one line to give the library&apos;s name and a brief idea of what it does.&gt;&#xA;Copyright (C) &lt;year&gt;  &lt;name of author&gt;&#xA;&#xA;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA  02110-1301  USA&#xA;&#xA;Also add information on how to contact you by electronic and paper mail.&#xA;&#xA;You should also get your employer (if you work as a programmer) or your&#xA;school, if any, to sign a &quot;copyright disclaimer&quot; for the library, if&#xA;necessary.  Here is a sample; alter the names:&#xA;&#xA;Yoyodyne, Inc., hereby disclaims all copyright interest in the&#xA;library `Frob&apos; (a library for tweaking knobs) written by James Random Hacker.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;signature of Ty Coon&gt;, 1 April 1990&#xA;Ty Coon, President of Vice&#xA;&#xA;That&apos;s all there is to it!'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.feature.jar' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='feature' version='1.0.0'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.update.feature' name='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf'/>
      </provides>
      <filter>
        (org.eclipse.update.install.features=true)
      </filter>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='org.eclipse.update.feature' id='gnu.io.rxtx' version='2.1.7.4_v20071016-7B57e7UAXMAAqGAGf'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='1'>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
      <licenses size='1'>
        <license uri='%25licenseURL' url='%25licenseURL'>
          %license
        </license>
      </licenses>
      <copyright uri='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html' url='http://www.rxtx.org/credits.html'>
        %copyright
      </copyright>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20071015)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.macosx' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.macosx&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20071015&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
    <unit id='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015' singleton='false'>
      <update id='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' range='[0.0.0,2.1.7.3_v20071015)' severity='0'/>
      <properties size='1'>
        <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.partial.iu' value='true'/>
      </properties>
      <provides size='3'>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
        <provided namespace='osgi.bundle' name='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
        <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='bundle' version='1.0.0'/>
      </provides>
      <artifacts size='1'>
        <artifact classifier='osgi.bundle' id='gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc' version='2.1.7.3_v20071015'/>
      </artifacts>
      <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
      <touchpointData size='1'>
        <instructions size='2'>
          <instruction key='manifest'>
            Bundle-SymbolicName: gnu.io.rxtx.solaris.sparc&#xA;Bundle-Version: 2.1.7.3_v20071015&#xA;Bundle-ManifestVersion: 2&#xA;Manifest-Version: 1.0&#xA;
          </instruction>
          <instruction key='zipped'>
            true
          </instruction>
        </instructions>
      </touchpointData>
    </unit>
  </units>
</repository>
